[music]
Heat up here.
>> [music]
>> Hello cats and kittens. How are you
doing?
And welcome [laughter]
to an election night live stream. I
doubt any of us will forget. I am the
host of this evening's stream, the
winner of the New York City mayoral
race, Curtis Leewa. [laughter]
Yes, I am repurposing my Halloween
costume because the real victor of this
evening is our favorite spoiler
candidate, Curtis Leewa, who it seems by
according to polls from at least earlier
today was slated to get about 17% of the
vote v vote voters that were more likely
to vote for Andrew Cuomo than for
Zoramani,
thus really presenting himself as
someone who deserves all of us to do our
caps to him, not for his substantive
politics, of course, though you might be
a fan of his love of cats, but for the
role that he played in this particular
election. Now, as you know, we are
shortly going to be joined by Amanda
Seals. She's gonna stick around with us
as we watch how people are reacting,
overreacting to uh the presumed win of
Zuron mom Donnie. But before she
arrives, I want to set up a little bit
of what's been going on in the
zeitgeist, perhaps provoked by the
popularity of Zoron and the
inevitability of his win. There have
been a slate of really insane articles
over the last few days uh in which
people have centrists I should say more
specifically have been desperate to
reclaim narrative control. We saw this
emerge after the 2024 election in the
form of the abundists. uh the folks who
were presenting the alternative to the
Joe Biden Kla Harris brand of politics
as a sort of a rebranded neoliberal
neoliberalism, the abundance book uh by
Ezra Klene and sorry just checking on on
Amanda uh by Ezra Klene who has also
accompanied the book uh along with Alex
Thompson. Sorry, not Alex Thompson,
Derek Thompson. Sorry, wrong wrong
Thompson. With a series of articles in
the New York Times about why centrism is
the way to go. Uh, one of them most
recently on November 2nd is titled,
"This is the way you beat Trump and
Trumpism."
Hold on, hold on to your hats. You'll
never guess. [laughter]
Hold on to your red beretss if you will.
You'll never guess what his prescription
is. The article starts, "Inside the
Democratic Party and its back rooms and
its group chats, its conferences and its
online flame wars, an increasingly
bitter debate has taken hold over what
the party needs to become to beat back
Trumpism. Does it need to be more
populist, more moderate, more socialist,
embrace the abundance agenda, produce
more vertical video?" The answer is yes.
Yes to all of it, but to none of it in
particular. The Democratic Party does
not need to choose one thing. It needs
to choose to be more things. And it will
not surprise you to learn that some of
the more things he encourages Democrats
to embrace are abandoning constituency
groups, including uh pro-choice groups,
uh trans folks, and of course, not
fullthroatedly embracing the sort of
economic populism that polls really big,
like Medicare for all, taxing the rich,
or minimum wage raise. These things take
a backseat to much more milktoast
prescriptions. Not to be left out, there
is a big piece in New York magazine
which generally speaking is one of the
better outlets in terms of advancing uh
progressive politics. This piece written
by Simon van Zulan Wood is titled
socialism or abundance two visions fight
for the Democratic Party's soul as it
searches for purpose direction and a
modicum of popularity. This piece begins
thusly and I see Amanda is in the room
and we're going to bring her on in just
one second. But I think this is
important to understand the broader
context of this election tonight and why
so many people are melting down and what
the stakes of of an election where a
candidate wins on a economic populist
agenda without running away from the
fact that he's an e democratic socialist
really means for the brand of centrist
politics that's been foisted on our
country uh for the last 40 years or so.
This one starts thusly. Since last
November's election defeat, the
Democratic party has been subject to an
endless battery of post-mortems, and a
shadow primary is already being fought
over who's got the formula to bring it
back to life. Michigan Senator Ellis
Ellis Slotkin characterized the party's
image as weak and woke and in need of
alpha energy. P. Buddha judge grew a
beard and blasted DEI style training as
something out of Portlandia. Not to be
outdone on the regular Joe front,
Arizona Senator Ruben Ggo explained that
every Latino man wants a big truck,
excuse me, a big ass truck.
Massachusetts Congressman Jake Ashenos
countered that such gestures are
derivative. Quote, Diet Coke populism
and won't beat Trump as his own game.
While California Governor Gavin Newsome
has overtly been trying to beat Trump at
his own game with a new keyboard warrior
persona that speaks in all caps. The
article goes on to say that so uh
socialism as evidenced by the popularity
of both Zaramani uh and the Bernie AOC
oligarchy rallies seems to show some
hope. But of course the abundance
faction also is putting forth their own
brand of politics. And this article
debates whether or not one or the other
is more likely to succeed. Of course
tonight counts a big win in the
socialism column. Here to discuss that
and also talk about her new book, a new
project that she's been working on and
that will premiere in just a few days on
November 8th is the one and only
activist, comedian, and very warm,
delightful, and funny woman, Amanda
Seals. Welcome, Amanda.
Amanda, why is it that I can't hear you?
Oh, okay. I Your mic's not muted on my
end. Okay, she's going to go up back and
come back in.
No worries there. Sometimes these things
happen.
>> An annoying day.
>> Oh, there you go. There you go. No
worries at all.
>> My rocaster is being done. This is just
an annoying day. It's annoying day.
Okay. I'm not delightful today. I'm not
[laughter] warm. Biana, I was here at 7.
I was here at 6:58. You sent me the
wrong link, baby.
>> I know. I know.
>> I was sitting in the other I was sitting
in a live you did the other day and I
looked up and I was like, that says
three hours. She been sitting on the
three hours.
>> You're completely right. You're
completely right. That was the link you
sent me. So, you thought you hadn't sent
me the link, but you had.
>> Okay. My
>> second guess yourself. I can't hear
anything you're saying. Just so you
know.
>> Wait, you can't.
>> I'm about to be able to hear what you're
saying. I had to reboot my entire
system.
>> Okay. You the audience, you guys can
hear me though, right?
>> I'm getting attacked by the Zionist
today. I'm just annoyed.
>> Wait, talk talk to us about what's been
going on. We texted about it briefly and
I saw you did a story about it on
Instagram.
>> You can hear me now.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. H help us understand because this
also is important context for folks who
might not be as familiar with you, who
didn't listen to you when you were on
Bad Faith last time, who who don't have
a have any context for how the
establishment
sort of media sphere has punished you
and sort of Hollywood has punished you
for your advocacy for Palestine. What's
been going on?
What's what's been going on with the
Zionist attacks today?
>> Can you hear me?
>> I can hear you. Yes. Okay. Um,
so I am heading out
to share my book with the people. Uh, I
haven't been on the road
in quite some time because of the
Zionists because last year,
uh, let's see. So, it all started in
March of last year where there was this
concerted like coordinated effort to
discredit me by calling me unlikable.
So, this was like all black media sites.
>> Like, I mean, I have to laugh because
it's just like which is why I love that
you're like the warm delightful.
[laughter]
Look, being warm and delightful doesn't
mean you always have to have a big, you
know, permanent smile on your face.
>> It also means that it doesn't mean that
you put up with nonsense either.
>> Exactly. Exactly.
>> Right. And that's what a lot of people
really want. Like they just want you to
be amanable
um to whatever they are dishing you and
you're just like, yeah, I'm I'm not
really for that. Like I don't feel like
there has to be any reason for me to go
along with nonsense if it's nonsense.
So, that being said, um I said, "Okay,
I'm going to
keep pushing forward." They tried to
like discredit me and, you know, do all
this nonsense, but okay, whatever. And
then I said, "Okay, you know what I'm
going to do? I'm going to go on Shannon
Sharp's show."
>> And that was when that was like a thing
to do. I know it sounds crazy, y'all. I
know. But it was at a time. So, I went
on pre that this was pre him
accidentally creating a little mini
porno film.
>> You know what's funny is that that was
not accidental. I don't believe that.
Like, no one's phone is just on like
that. Like, let's keep it a buck, y'all.
Like, what are we talking about?
>> Wait, wait. For those who don't know
what happened,
>> please give them context.
>> Okay, so this is this is my recollection
of it. Tell me if I get any of the facts
wrong. Basically, he started an
Instagram live where it became clear
that his phone, while you couldn't see
what was what was happening, you could
hear basically him having sex with
somebody.
>> In what world?
I do Instagram live a lot. [laughter]
>> And there ain't no accidental start to
an Instagram live. [laughter]
It asks you three different like you
know what I'm saying? Like I feel like
they've they've considered that there's
a contingency. You got to press this and
you got to press this and you got to
press this. [laughter]
>> Right. Okay. So, he he I guess his
response to it would have happened was
like this was an accident. He didn't
want to lose jobs and all those kinds of
things. He's a former football player
and is I guess
>> I don't believe none of that. I think
that he was literally just doing that to
uh try to curtail what he knew was
coming down which was that this woman
was going to accuse him of mistreatment.
And so that was an attempt to
demonstrate, look, you know, it's not
mistreatment, whatever. I don't care.
Um, to be quite honest, like, she was
19. Like, what are you doing?
>> Oh, really?
>> And he's like, he's got to be close to
60.
>> I love that you looked at your watch.
>> Sorry. I just kind of [laughter]
whatever it was, it was perfect timing.
He's got to be close to 60,
right? Um, so yes, but nonetheless, the
point I brought, the point of me
bringing it up was because I went on the
show and then that kind of kept me un
unintentionally in like the zeitgeist of
things. Um, and then shortly there, but
I was also like about to go on tour for
uh for what I had named the unlikable
tour. So, I was doing standup. So, I
went on the quote unquote unlikable tour
and then they started the Zionist
started calling the venues that I was
performing at and trying to get them
>> to cancel my shows, which they
successfully did at some venues. Um,
there was like a 2,000 email campaign in
Detroit. They had a truck. I've told you
this story, I think, before that they
had a truck with my name on the side
with my face on the side that said
Amanda Seals the Jew hater. I am not.
Um,
>> of course,
>> WE ALWAYS HAVE TO SAY IT. I MEAN, I know
it's annoying, but it is what it is. Um,
>> yeah. [snorts]
>> So, long story short,
>> their goal is to take your livelihood
from you. That is their because they
only think because it's a limited
Zionists have a very limited minds
mindset, right? Like their only version
of humanity is what they decide is human
and their only concept of humanity is
transactional. It's a very very myopic
mindset. And so they're like, "Oh,
that's what we'll do. We'll just take
money from her." And so I said, "Oh,
I'll just do free shows."
So I started doing this one woman show
called What Would the Ancestors Say. And
first we started doing a couple shows
that were actually still ticketed, but
we did them at venues that were very
much down with like we're not going to
let them cancel you, cancel the show,
etc. Like we understand the movement.
And uh then I started doing the show at
the People's Forum for free here in New
York City. And I had a book at Simon and
Schustster. I had a memoir at Simon and
Schustster that I decided to buy back
from them when my editor
showed that she was shady and also had
some Zionist rhetoric going on. And then
they wanted me to cut 75,000 words from
my 150,000word book because they said my
contract was only for 70,000 75,000
words. And it, you know, and there and
it was a lot going on with that. But I
say all of that to say
that in this time period I also have
just been unrelent like unrelenting in
my support of Palestine in my support of
anti-fan in in my anti in my Antifa uh
[laughter]
>> in my
um and I really haven't allowed for it
to dull my
like I'm not afraid of them. And I think
that's really what it boils down to.
They want to beat you back. So now I'm
headed out with I decided to actually
write What would the ancestors say?
After performing it on stage,
I decided that it did it. It did. Oh, I
sent you the book. I pulled this off the
internet. I You sent me the tour dates
and I'm trying to figure out the book
earlier today.
>> I sent you the image.
>> Yeah, you did. Is this not it?
That's a flyer, but that's not the book.
>> Look, you're gonna have to you're gonna
have to be patient with me, Amanda,
because I don't have a producer. I'm
doing all of this while trying to
engage.
>> I do the same thing every Wednesday at
10 a.m. Eastern, y'all. So, make sure
you watch Views from Amanda.
>> I am trying to figure out how to get the
image that you sent me
>> into a format that this site will
acknowledge and allow me to. But I'm I'm
Yes, it is not easy. Please don't Let's
not have a whole conversation about it.
But I'm I'm trying to do that while
you're talking. I promise. I'm trying so
hard. Um, but in
>> I can also like help you is what I'm
saying.
>> No, no, go ahead. I want you to keep
talking. So, because I don't want the
convers I don't want to bore everybody
with the background noise, but that I I
promise that I'm that I'm trying. Um,
but go ahead.
>> I don't think you're not trying. But you
are getting irritated though. And I'm
really just trying to tell you because
>> No, no, [laughter] come on. I go ahead
and keep telling them about what's going
on. Uh, I saw that you your live today
about the um about what's going on with
your tour dates and about how they're
trying to buy up the free tickets on uh
all the not buy up but like you know
occupy the space of all the free tickets
on your tour dates.
Well, I
learned today that I guess there's an
era of there's a a element of Reddit
Reddit that I guess is the Zionist
Reddit and uh they're on there
having a Zioblast and basically
reserving all because the the book
events are free. So, they're on there
reserving
all of the tickets so that I'll have an
empty room. However, the reality is that
y'all can show up. [laughter] I mean,
it's there's not it's not tickets. I I
am not selling tickets. So, feel free to
show up. You can go to amanda seals.com
and you can come right there. And uh
I'll be in San Diego on Wednesday. I
will be in Seattle on the 10th. I will
be in Detroit on the 11th. And I will be
in Chicago on the 12th. So,
you know, feel free to show up. And I
think it's very um
I think there's I think it's very First
of all, people in here are like, "You
came off irritated." I came on the live
irritated. I am irritated. I am IN A
STATE OF irritation right now. That's
what [laughter] I I don't think Y'ALL
UNDERSTAND. LIKE, IT'S NOT it's not
Briana irritating me. I am irritated.
[laughter]
I THOSE [ __ ] Zionists constantly
trying to RUIN MY LIFE WHILE THEY ARE
AREN'T you all busy enough genociding an
entire like an entire people.
>> Yeah.
>> Multiple people's. So like yeah I am
irritated by Nicholas Turner.
>> Like speaking speaking of Amanda, did
you catch any of the um the meltdown
from uh Deborah uh what's her name from?
>> Dylan Grace. Yeah, Deborah Messing. How
could I forget messing with the messy
last name? [laughter] Apparently people
were screen grabbing it. She had like a
hundred dashes in her Instagram story
melting down
today about about Zoran Mandani.
>> What I at this point I'm just like what?
They're [laughter] so psychotic.
>> It's really true. So I I'll pull it up
too. I'll pull this up too, but one of
the ones that made it over to the
Twitter sphere was a truly uh
unconscionable
um screen grab that in which she was
basically in vain about how Islam is a
categorically inferior religion that in
incentivizes people to lie as a as
opposed to Christianity and Judaism.
>> What?
>> And and she is not being cancelled by
>> Hollywood. No.
>> Yep. Here, I'm gonna pull another
>> because because Hollywood is Zionists.
That's what a lot of people don't
actually understand. Like Hollywood
itself is run by Zionists and some
people in the past would say Hollywood
is run by Jewish people. And that's just
not accurate because it's a specific
polit politic that's running
the actual Z like the actual systems
that we are watching. Yeah. Here here
are two things that she put out on her
Instagram and has since deleted. One is
this graphic. I hadn't seen this one
before saying called titled things we
don't see Jews doing. Flying planes into
buildings trying to dominate the world.
>> Really? That we DON'T SEE THEM DOING
THAT.
>> I mean, GIRL, IT'S LIKE SHE'S BING.
>> It's always the way. It's all the the Oh
my god. So, real quick though, I was at
my storage unit earlier and I'm wearing
a shirt that says Israel is a settler
state. And there was this like Finnish
from Finland man who was in like the
unit next to me. And so
I he had these like two little lamps on
the ground. I was very taken by the
lamps. And so I [laughter] started I was
I was just making conversation. I was
like, "Oh, I really like your lamps."
And I could but he was like distracted
and he was like, "Oh, the I don't know
how to do a Finnish accent, so sorry if
it sounds French."
>> [laughter]
>> So he's like, "But you are wearing a
beret." So I feel like that's also why
it sounds French. Um, and so he's like,
"The lamps, oh yes, yes, the lamps." And
and I could feel that he was like trying
to like get something out. And finally
he was like, "Oh,
you're wearing a shirt for Israel."
Now, these are the moments where you're
like, "Do I feel like having a
revolution up in the storage unit
today?" And the answer is yes.
>> [laughter]
>> And
comrade Steel said at all times
[laughter] at all
in something. And so I said, "Um, this
is not an Israel shirt. You see what
this shirt says?" And then he's reading
it and he's like, "Oh, that is it." I
said, "This is a pro Palestine shirt.
[laughter] This is A FREE PALESTINE
SHIRT. That's what this shirt is." I
also knew there was cameras. So if he
was going to try and get frisky, my dog
was there with me. Literally, my dog
Jordy was there. So I I you know, Jordy
was going to do his thing.
>> So then I was like, and then so there's
always that moment, right, where you're
not sure where it's going to go. And he
was like,
"Yes, you know, I I trans I I uh
converted to Judaism in my last
marriage. Now I'm Russian. I'm just
giving you various accents. [laughter]
None of them none of them Scandinavian.
Hey, close enough. They sure border.
[laughter]
>> And then he was like, he was like, "My I
I converted to Judaism in my last
marriage." He was like, "And now I feel
I feel bad like I don't want to be a Jew
anymore." And I said to him, I said,
"It's not about being Jewish. It's about
being Zionist."
>> Yeah,
>> that's specifically what it's about. And
he was like, "You're right." And I was
like, because we must understand that
the folks that are using Judaism
in in their effort to be Zionists are
absolutely not Jewish. They are
completely disregarding, disrespecting
the actual faith. And he was like,
exactly, exactly. You see what's going
on? It is terrible what's going on. And
they're using this and and and he was
like, you know, [sighs]
you know, Israel shouldn't even exist.
And I was like, man, brother, you you
met the right one in this storage
[laughter] unit.
>> Oh, I love that, Amanda. You thought it
was about to be a conflict, but you gave
it because I know where I live.
>> And that's what he said. That's what he
said when he was leaving. He was like,
I'm giving you my card because it's it's
so nice to be able to have this
conversation.
>> Yeah.
>> And not just [clears throat] have it
here, here, here. And I was like, yeah,
anytime. Anytime. Finish, brother.
Anytime. [laughter]
Well, God God bless him because I I
thought the story was going to go a
different way because you know they'd
say what like there's there's no there's
no one as zealous as the convert.
There's no one as faithful as the you
know about how people who you know come
to a faith will be
>> oh yes like they go the hardest
>> they go the hardest right like Charlotte
on Sex in the City.
>> But I I really love the ending to the
story because Deborah Messing is one I
got to say. I mean this whole thing
number five forcing young girls to marry
old men like has SEINFELD ENTERED THE
CHAT
>> HAS WOODY Allen entered the chat like
what are we doing
>> like this is
>> this is nonsense
>> this is this is
>> EPSTEIN ENTERED THE CHAT
>> RIGHT LIKE DON'T DON'T MAKE US DO DON'T
MAKE US DO THIS Debbie
>> do it
>> okay and then this is the one
you call her [laughter] Debbie
>> Debs
Deborah this is this is the one that was
really taking people out earlier today.
She says, "In Judaism and Christianity,
we are commanded to speak the truth. In
Islam, they are commanded to lie. If it
means spreading Islam, do not uh
disregard the fundamental ideological
difference." Now, take a look at Mum
Donnie. Apply that basic rule. Listen to
his words, then watch his actions. He's
revealing their goal, mass conversion.
These two opposing civilizations cannot
exist.
This this is a woman in good standing,
>> right? and her professional millia,
>> right? Nice use a millu. Nice use a
millu. I appreciate it. I I just You
always have the good words, too. You
know, you know, I love a vocab.
>> I mean, but like this is I appreciate
it. Thank you. But this is this is
honestly nuts. And I I do feel like I
you know that my audience knows that
I've I've been cautiously optimistic
about Zoramani. I have given a lot of
space to criticisms of certain
retrenchments of his in the course of
this campaign. I have criticized his
unwillingness to stand behind his
criticisms of the NYPD as racist the
same way that he stood behind his
commitments to Palestine. Yes. And I
have also
>> had a little bit of an eye twitch about
some softening of language around the
arresting of Netanyahu and the like.
Like I've seen it all and we'll have
more time to talk about that later in
the show if people want to talk about
that. But it's stuff like this with
Deborah Messing and the entire
billionaire class coming down on Mum
Donnie that does make this day feel
momentous.
Even if it's not about advancing the
left's broader, more revolutionary and
less reformist goals, it certainly is a
deadly blow to the
what up until this point has been
complete
ideological
a demand for complete ideological
commitment to Zionism in the public
sphere. That those days are over. When a
Muslim
man wins
the race for mayor of New York after
soundly winning the primary and whooping
a former governor of New York, Andrew
Cuomo, who had all the name recognition,
who himself is a Nepo baby, who has
billionaires backing him up to the hilt,
>> the governor
>> and who was the governor? who was the
governor whose father
>> LIKE NAMED AFTER HIS father [laughter]
>> you're and and the audacity of him to be
calling Zaramani a nepo baby is just
[laughter]
so it makes you like this this is this
is a win for pro Palestinian narratives
it just it just is and it is a win in
terms of it revealing the weakness of
the ADL and all of these other proionist
organizations who have been working
overtime to prevent this from happening
and that's why they're freaking out and
that's why this is a bit of a victory
lap day regardless of our like the
broader criticism of
>> official though that he won right?
>> No, no, no, no. He's just up. Let me
bring up that poll I had up earlier. Go
ahead.
>> If he loses
>> Yeah.
>> and nobody does nothing,
[ __ ] y'all. Like I I just I
because there's no The thing is is that
it's not even that he I think you're
actually giving Quuomo too much credit
when you say that he beat him soundly.
He didn't even have to do anything. Like
Cuomo beat him like he beat himself. The
amount of flubs and just nonsense that
he was doing like he didn't even have to
really say anything. This man is like
New York has been ruining this the head
of New York has been ruining the the
city. It's like you you are the head of
New York. Like what are we talking
about? And then when he misnomer
Eugene for Jonathan K part on the news
on the on whatever mainstream media. Did
you see that?
>> Wait, I missed that.
>> Oh, you will love it.
>> Eugene,
>> you love it. So he was on some MSNBC
something or other CNN, MSNBC, one of
those things. And there was two brothers
and a white woman. So it was Eugene I
>> strength diversity be a strength. That
was that one.
>> Okay, let me let me pull up let me pull
up that video in a second because that
was really funny. Let me throw this up
on the screen real quick though while
I've got it got it here. And mom wasn't
even there. Mond wasn't even there. Th
this is why this is why I'm talking
about this as though it's a fate
accomply. Although of course you're
right. I don't think the polls have
closed. My brother just sent me a a
selfie of himself with his I voted
sticker. He's the only one in the family
still left in New York. So like, thank
you, brother. My literal brother. Um,
but the these are the numbers that we
were seeing earlier in the day. On the
left, you have the number of people who
voted early in the 2021 mayoral race.
[laughter] On the right, you have the
number who voted early in the 2025
mayoral race. And as you can see,
>> nuts.
>> It's like, what? I'm not good at math.
They're like three or four times bigger.
>> Oh, you're not good at math either. It's
just it's beyond me.
>> I would have been a doctor if I could do
some numbers, but instead like all bad
mathematicians, I went to law school.
>> All right, so you can see like this is
this is why this is why there's a
freakout, right? This this is it. Okay,
so let me see if I can find this uh
Eugene clip. Oh, but one one more while
I still have this up up. Actually, let
me take this down so y'all don't see all
of my uh pinned
[laughter] what what I why would I be
pinning up in here? But this is also an
indication of what's going on. Everybody
is bending the knee now. So, I didn't
see this. This is Jamie Rasin.
>> A whole slate of mainstream Democrats
have been saying things like, "Well, I
endorse the Democratic mom and
specifically saying mom Donnie." But
this is what we're getting now from
Jamie Rasin. You've been able to scare a
lot of people. Socialist. He's a
democratic socialist. He's an FDR
[music] Democrat.
>> Gross.
>> Some reporters give me a hard time. You
said like he's accomplished what FDR
said. I said, "No, he's at the beginning
of his career. He's got Roosevelt
ambition." [laughter]
Is that all right with you?
>> That was the highest they've ever seen.
>> Well, I I've been talking a lot about
Roosevelt. You know, when he made that
famous speech in 1932 at the convention
where the lords of capital all hate me,
they announced me. They attack me. I
welcome
I love to pretend like FPR was not
racist with the working people.
>> Well, look, this is this is one of the
this is one of the questions here. Let
me take this down.
This is one of the issues that I teed up
in the beginning, right? Because now
we're in the middle of this debate about
where the Democratic party goes from
here. and the centrist dim, the
mainstream establishment dims are
desperate to figure out a way to
neutralize the obvious enthusiasm around
Mum Donnie, the popularity of around Mam
Donnie. How do you not come off as a
hater? Right? Because Chuck Schumer and
um what's his name? Our the
>> team Jeffiest
[ __ ]
him and Corey it's it's Ren and 10.
>> It's it's a race to the bottom of the
corny barrel.
>> It's 10.
like they're they are completely out of
touch and nobody wants to look as bad as
they're looking. So what you what you're
getting is a lot of people saying things
like I appreciate what Mumini has been
able to do in terms of turnout. The
Democrats need this kind of enthusiasm.
I appreciate how he's coming out against
Donald Trump. Donald Trump who of course
endorsed Cuomo within the last 24 hours
which Mom Donnie very smartly turned
around and promoted as uh a kind of a
mask off moment for the politics that
Cuomo represents.
But
>> wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait. Cuz I've been running around
all day
and it took me a minute to process what
you just said.
>> Yep.
Okay. So, I see people there's some
people who are like, "This guy isn't
going to do anything substantive." And
we're having a conversation that is
above Montani as an individual. And so I
want y'all to to join us in that
conversation because what we are really
watching is a party like the the concept
of parties and who's in what realm etc
becomes untenable when you have Donald
Trump
doing the
uh endorsing of a candidate who
Democrats have soundly endorsed in favor
of somebody that is supposedly a part of
or or or that they are supposed to be a
part of alignment with. So how do you
honestly reconcile
Democrats are leftists,
[clears throat]
right? Because that's what he keeps
saying that Democrats are these like
radical leftists while
>> while you are endorsing someone who was
just running as a Democrat the other
day.
>> The other day.
>> Yeah. and who has always been a Democrat
>> like familiarly, right? How how does
that and so that's the kind of stuff
that you see when folks are like clawing
at whatever. And this is why folks like
Briana and I are constantly trying to
get folks to consider beyond because
these folks are already beyond. Dick
Cheney died today
and
he endorsed Kamla.
>> Yep. That's such an important point. Th
this I'm going to put this up in a
second, but there was a woman uh named
Emily May who tweeted this out a couple
of days ago or yesterday. She tweeted,
"Cuomo being endorsed by Trump proves
what leftists have been saying for ages,
that establishment Democrats still
protect most of the same corporate
interests as conservatives. They just
stick a pride flag on it." Like this
this endorsement reveals what we've
always been saying is true, which is
that is that there are corporate
interests that supersede any of these
party interests. And when push comes to
shove, if there's ever someone running
as a Democrat, whether it's Zoron or
Bernie, who comes close to actually
talking about some of the systemic
change, people go mask off and reveal
their two true colors. This is what Mani
had to say about it, I believe, this
morning on CNN.
>> Zoran Mani, thank you very much.
Obviously, we're hours away. Yes. Hours
away here. Are you Are you ready? Do you
expect it's going to be a big night for
you?
>> I'm hopeful. I'm confident, but I'll
never be complacent. But look, if people
want to vote for Donald Trump and Elon
Musk, they should vote for Andrew Cuomo.
If people want to vote for change, they
should vote for me.
>> All right, Zoran M. Donnie. [laughter]
I wonder who in the camp put that
sentence together. Just run it. Just run
it. [laughter]
Run it. There it is.
>> That was a, you know, that was a solid
mic drop. I MEAN, HE'S A RAPPER, RIGHT?
Don't he be rapping? So, you know what
though, Briana? like
>> all of
>> the Democrats were there before the
Republicans, right? Like the Democrats
are very staunchly a part of American
history. American history has staunchly
always been about corporatism. The
individuals who began the United States
were extreme capitalists who were slave
owners who started the country based on
we want to keep all the money we're
making and not give it to you. That was
the concept. Like I know it gets
presented as this like RAH RAH SHISH
BOOM BA WE'RE REBELS when really it was
just like nah we don't like that we
paying taxes and y'all not representing
us so we're actually going to just start
our own joint because we're making all
of this money and y'all don't deserve
our money. So this is a country that
whenever they talk about LIKE GOOD OLD
AMERICAN VALUES, those are the values.
The values are making money, making
money off the backs of free labor, that
is the value of this country. And
Democrats have been here longer in that
mindset. And so, you know, the the the
MAGA likes to say stuff like that, but
what I'm saying is the fact that the
Democrats have been here from that
moment in time should let you know that
they are not an opposition party.
They're the actual
like tent pole. MAGA is their opposition
party who's like, "Let's take it even
more." Right. So, it's not it's not
about reforming the Democrats. It's not
about like, "Why aren't the Democrats
behaving like such and such?" They are
doing exactly what has been their main
frame to do. And they're really looking
at MAGA like dang like y'all took our
spot because for since RA I mean since
uh Nixon and the Southern Strategy
>> Yeah.
>> you know they were basically just like
oh we're just not as racist as y'all.
>> 100%. 100%. which is why so part of
what's happening in this you know big
debate over you know what way the
Democratic party should go is one is
just neutralize Zoron like neutralize
the left and the abundance movement
although they deny it up down and center
is all about creating a label for
something that feels different from what
just lost that is not the Bernie
movement that actually has as its core
anti-oligarchy which is a message that
you can't split the baby on right you
can't say the whole messages about
corporate greed and taxing the very rich
and being anti- oligarchy, but also be
against taxing the rich. But you can
definitely be pro-abundance and against
taxing the rich because abundance at the
end of the day, they say it's all about
um getting rid of red tape. It is a
message that aligns with the sort of
small government Republican stances.
Sure, is there government waste? There's
does there exist inefficiencies in every
system? of course and this is what
Bernie acknowledged in this article and
that the abundists were running with
saying even Bernie likes us and they did
the same thing with Zuron when he went
on one of their shows. he uh you know
agreed with some narrow part of the
agenda which is okay of course you know
we do need to build more houses and as
some municipalities there are
prohibitions against doing so that we
should look at of course but what the
broader abundance messages is to say
let's get rid of any and all regulations
and this with the singular goal of
building more housing and let's let
private public parts and corporations do
what they want to do and they are
unwilling to look at
>> that's actually not abundance
>> right and they're they're fundamentally
unwilling to look at the role that
corporations ations play, you know,
Blackwater, all the people that are
buying up all of the house, Black
Rockck, corporations play in the housing
crisis and in the affordability crisis
whatsoever. And people like Derek
Thompson will explicitly say when that
stuff is brought up, oh, it's not about
oligarchy. Oligarchy isn't going to fix
this. And Ezra Klein's article, he says,
well, the reason that housing is more
affordable in Texas versus California
isn't because of oligarch because Texas
got away with oligarchy. It's like
they're being paid to miss the point. So
that, you know, and so then so what they
do
>> I think that's actually accurate. I
think they are being paid to miss the
point though.
>> They're 100%. [laughter]
That's actually true. So, uh, a friend
of the show, Aaron Reaganberg, he's been
on talking about the abundance stuff a
couple of times in the last six months.
He just wrote a new piece called
deciding to fold in, uh, the nation in
which he breaks down this what what the
abundance crew has been pushing for,
including during that abundance
conference they had a couple of months
ago. They have this pack called welcome
pack that has released this white paper
called deciding to win which is a 59page
memo in which they put forth their
vision of how the democrats could win
and unsurprisingly it is to be moderate
moderate moderate just to move to the
middle middle and at the end of this
piece Erin does a good job of sort of
summarizing the left's case in the
alternative which is to point out that
there are all of these policies which
are enormously popular that somehow the
Ezra Kleins of the world magically
forget about every time they talk about
moving toward where Americans are and
what Americans want, including Medicare
for all, taxing the rich and minimum
wage, all of these other kinds of
things. Um, and points out that it is
the liberals, not the left, that
overindexed on cultural issues. Not that
those aren't important, but when you're
asking someone who has an economic
crisis to prioritize cultural issues,
then they get mad. They're not even
necessarily mad at the cultural issue.
They're mad that they feel like their
more pressing economic issue isn't going
to be addressed. So, the abundance are
claiming on one of these pieces. I'll
find the direct quote in a second that
you've lost black people. You've lost
you've lost black people going hard on
defund the police. You've lost Latinos
going to the left on immigration. You've
lost women going to the left on abortion
rights. As though correlation is
causation, as though it's not. You left
working-class people in all of those
groups. Yes.
>> Over represented in all of those groups,
women, minorities, etc. Precisely
because you haven't been willing to do
the things that would make their lives
materially better. facts. But that's the
thing. I I feel
it's all it's all a spin all the time.
It's it's actually quite uh dizzying.
>> Yep.
>> Because we're always having to reset the
retrograde like they're always doing
this uh the propaganda is so abundant.
[laughter]
Nice.
>> Mhm. Uh [laughter]
that I find I find it actually at this
point a needle in a hay sack to find a
straight ahead
story written or a straight ahead take
um coming from these spaces. I we were
in a space similar we were in a space
recently where
>> it just feels like how do I put this? It
just feels like
there's the people that are actually
living life and then like having to like
exist and then there's the people who
are talking about the people that are
actually having to exist but they're not
talking to each other.
>> So they're just in this like weird uh
silo that is completely devoid of the
actual realities and they're fine with
that. And I see that on both sides. I
see that not just from people who are
talking nonsense of abundance, but I
even see that from people who think that
they're really being like progressive,
but they're still disconnected. Um, I
saw someone say like I saw someone's
earlier today I was on live on Instagram
and uh this person was like, you know, I
I I'm on Snap and I'm not going to get
my SNAP benefits. And then later in the
live they were like, I love Kla Harris.
And I was like, [sighs]
[laughter]
well, look, if Kamla Harris, instead of
celebrating the Chenies, as she
continued to do today, had not been
touring the country and going to
Dearborn with Liz Cheney.
>> There you go.
>> But instead had, I don't know, broken
from Biden on Gaza, she could have won
won three states, swing states. Yes.
Yes,
>> that was the number one issue for 2020
voters who declined to vote in 2024, the
genocide in Gaza. And
>> she also had nothing about working-class
people in her policies.
>> It was all about middle class. Yep. This
I'm going to get the middle class back.
>> Yep.
>> Have more babies and I'll give you some
money.
>> Yep.
>> She loves She loves to do a policy. This
is from 2020, so apologies for me to be
still so 2020 brain, but that was the
one I worked on so I remember all the
details. But she had this housing policy
back then where I swear to God it was
something like if you own a business in
a low-income neighborhood for three
years and your tax returns show this
amount of money and you also have a
one-legged cat named Cleopatra and you
can hula hoop and hop on one leg for 15
minutes at a time, then you can get a
cat a rebate on your taxes in the amount
of $47.87.
It was the most like
>> So wait, so wait,
>> someone in your comment said, "What is
Mom Donniey's plan for FBA New Yorkers?"
Now, first of all, I consider the FBA
FBI. Any of y'all using that term, any
y'all calling any black people referring
to themselves FBA? I consider you FBI.
So, let's just know that that's where I
stand on that. However,
>> you've you've you've tangled with the
descendants, Amanda.
>> Oh, they're mad at you,
>> girl. The descendants
>> from having a Caribbean mom. Yes, honey.
They like who? MALCOLM X'S MOTHER. I'M
LIKE MALCOLM X'S mother from Grenada.
THEY'RE LIKE THAT'S DIFFERENT. IT'S
DIFFERENT. IT'S DIFFERENT. It's
different. Um [laughter]
>> so many people
>> Sorry.
>> It's like for people who know it's like
um it's like [ __ ] It's like uh uh
>> foundational black descendants of of
North American slavery of American
American slavery. I should say it's
Caribbean count as North America. I
don't know what continent.
>> No, it's not a continent. And what kind?
>> But it also like it centers under the
opices that there's somebody not it it
centers under the opaces that anyone
that other members of the diaspora are
not centering them. So that's the beef.
But
>> yeah, it's diaspora war. It's diaspora.
But to to
I was I wasn't I can't say I was
shocked, but there was such an effort by
quote unquote black leadership to also
slight Mom Donnie, right? To also use
identity politics
to push the Democrat agenda that never
shows up for black people. And so when
we talk about FBA, like you are
subscribing to identity politics. I just
want you to know that person in here
who's like, I'm FBA. And identity
politics is a ploy that is used to
castrate the ability for there to be
coalition building, the ability for you
to see the realities of policies beyond
blackness. And so it just it just gets
you roped into voting for people cuz
they black. And it's like that at that
that ship has sailed. We don't have
people. At one point in time when black
folks were showing up in political
spaces, it was as a political activist.
That's the only way like cuz you had to
go into that space knowing that you
could get mollywobbed. We not in that
time no more. [laughter]
>> They go in there knowing like
>> I hope you're right.
>> I'm sorry. They I mean folks go into
politics at this point like oh I can
come up like Nancy Pelosi came up mega
mills. I can come up if I work my way
up.
>> I hope that I mean I know people are
like, you know,
>> 100%.
>> Yeah,
>> Donnie is is different. I don't I don't
I haven't Here's my question for you,
Brianna Gory Gray. BJG,
>> please. Please.
When it comes to holding folks
accountable,
what are ways that the people can
actually hold elected officials
accountable? Because the only version
that folks end up saying back to me is
we won't vote for them next time. And
I'm like, that's a while.
>> Yeah,
it's it's a while. It also ignores the
power of incumbency and how once they
get their toll hold in, you'll have much
less leverage. So, this was the argument
that happened with AOC, right? It's
like, give her a chance, yada yada yada.
Okay, look, you know,
I I I never want to I know that my own
credibility is also kind of on the line
if I'm perceived as being unfair or to
judge prematurely. But I do think it's
our responsibility to judge concurrently
as the things are happening and to apply
pressure consistently, especially when
prior to being elected, they are more
vulnerable to our push back. Which is
why it's been so important to me not to
buy into the narrative that some of the
left has embraced over the course of
Mani's campaign, which is to say he has
to do what he has to do, just let it go,
etc., etc. The the other side isn't
doing that, right? The business lobby
that Aid Herd wrote about him meeting
with in that lengthy New York Times
profile from a couple of weeks ago isn't
waiting until he wins to press their
agenda. They're saying, "I'm going to
try to defeat your campaign unless you
bend the need our interest." the, you
know, all of these different groups of
Zionist New Yorkers, some of whom have
come around to Mumani who declare
themselves to be liberal Zionists and
are standing with him at the
podium, have pushed and prodded and
pressured him to get to a point where he
says he will reconsider and advise his
supporters not to use the phrase
globalized to antif,
>> right? They were able to hurt our guy.
lets him get away with saying that he no
longer thinks the racist NYPD is racist.
And we're supposed and to keep Jessica
Tish, the uh Eric Adams, Zionist New
York police commissioner
>> on board. And we're supposed to
[clears throat] just believe that she's
going to do his bidding once he's the
mayor. And that's that's what he told a
couple of pod lefty podcasters who, to
their credit, pressed him on this issue
during a live show. I I covered this on
a
recent episode of Bad Faith Podcast. I
think this was the one I did with um
was it with Matt McManus? One of the
recent episodes in the last week or two.
Uh so yeah, I think that you can see the
direction that Mani has name me one
thing that Mumani has gotten more bold
and more left on since he conclusively
won the Democratic primary.
>> I can't it's it's honestly
>> Okay. And ourselves why that is. It was
very much, oh, this is in the bag now.
It was very much that. It was very much,
oh, they in the bag now. And then these
other folks started coming for his neck.
And
instead to to me, I would have liked to
have seen him say,
"It's in the bag." Like, why why would I
even need to capitulate to you?
[laughter]
>> Exactly.
Exactly.
I've already
I don't mean to be like
>> I'm I'm with you.
And so we're gonna see what that looks
like. You're breaking up or I'm breaking
up.
>> I don't mean to be like Donald Trump
should be
>> Oh, sorry. I think it's me. I think I
have way too many um windows open and
I'm going to try to res
>> Mine looks like Deborah Messing's DM.
Mine looks like Deborah Messing stories.
So let me also do that.
We're both just closing tabs.
I can't hear you at all if you're
talking.
You sound like Transformers, robots in
disguise.
Oh, she's gone. [laughter]
She left.
Well, y'all, while I'm here, my book,
What Would the Ancestors Say, comes out
on Friday, I mean on Saturday. I'll be
doing a live stream performance and
reading of the full text one all the way
through as well as uh folks will get the
opportunity to get a signed copy of the
book with their ticket. So you can go to
amandaals.com to check that out. And
this book is uh something that I'm
really excited about because I feel like
I stumbled upon a new
genre. um it felt very
it felt like a a process that I had also
stumbled upon. And so for those who
don't know, I'm also a vis visual
artist. So, uh I've got some
illustrations here in the book and um
let me show you. Let's see. We've got
we've got Frederick. So the theme is
that they're all on the phone because
our ancestors are on call. And you know,
I believe that all of this that's going
on is beyond just a political
conversation. And my frustration, my
irritation as of right now is that I
feel like so many of us are in a
we're we're having these conversations
knowing that there's actually whole
other levels and so many folks are just
simply not considering that there's
other levels. And so we can't actually
get beyond this surface of analysis. So
yes, Amanda did do these drawings. Uh I
added a forward. There's also a
additional resources list in the back
with fil with books and films and essays
and speeches that are um that add to
that are I haven't eaten so that are
supplementary. Um this is what happens
when you have someone on the show that
has a show. So you was good. I was like
I hope she knows she's in good hands.
Don't stress. We got you beret. We got
>> I knew you would hold it down. I knew
you'll hold it down. Thank you very
much. Someone asked, "Who's the
publisher?"
>> I am the publisher. And I also want to
point out that
>> self-publishing
gets looked down upon by a lot of folks,
but in this specific day and age, and
it's always been this, but it's gotten
even clearer. We have to own our own IP.
These spaces, mega corporate spaces,
they are very much about having your IP
and running with it till the end and you
are fighting them for getting the
pittance that you are owed for
everything that you have put into this.
You know, I learned the inesign program
so I could actually lay out the book
myself and do so in a fashion that spoke
to me and I didn't want to have to argue
with nobody about it. This particular
page I'm very proud of because what I've
done here is these strands of of of text
are the names of Palestinians who have
been killed by state sanctioned violence
as well as black people in the United
States who have
oh
>> and so my goal sorry you I I understand
the struggle I'm in the struggle every
Wednesday [laughter]
views from land they be like take your
time sister take your time I be out in
the, you know, the mic ain't working,
etc. So, okay. Um,
>> so I just wanted to to everybody out
there who is considering a path as a
creative and you're like, dang, but I
need to have a big company behind me,
etc. I will say this,
even though I was on Insecure, it was
the stuff that I created on my own that
has allowed me to continue to fight the
Zionists, that has allowed me to
continue to extract myself from
capitalism because your your continue
your your creating doesn't stop. And uh
folks who like Zionists, they can't they
can't wrap their heads around that
because they create for the purpose of
capital only. and we're not about that
life. So, shout out to everybody who
supports independent artists, etc. You
can go to amassales.com
and uh Brianna Dre Gay, the great BJG.
Um I love I love the the the the way
that is in my mouth. BJG. Um
>> put up my tour. So, I am going to be in
those cities. San Diego, Los Angeles.
The tickets are sold out for the in
studio performance in Los Angeles, but
Seattle, Detroit, Chicago. The Zionists
are trying to shut it down. They're
trying to intimidate the organizations
that I'm working with. They're trying to
intimidate the venues that I'm going to
be at. And you know, the reality is is
that there's more of us than them. So, I
hope that you guys will show up and that
you will be proud in your keias and in
your dashikis and in your Adidas
tracksuits or whatever you feel
comfortable in. And um I'm going to be
there if there's two people or not. So,
that's going to be the that's that's how
that's going to go down. Well, you know
it's not going to be any two people
because there are almost a thousand
people in this chat watching you right
now. And I encourage you to follow the
advice of the ticker tape at the bottom
of the stream and to subscribe and hit
the bell. I am obviously a leite and
cannot figure a lot of things out today,
including how to co-stream to Amanda's
YouTube. So, also take a minute at some
point this evening to go over to sister
Brianna. I think honestly it's going to
let you do it after. I I genuinely feel
like that's what the vibe is. Well, I I
will do it after, but there's also a way
to do it concurrently. I've done it with
Katie before. I texted her. She was on
the road and then I texted her producer,
but he didn't get back to me. But it's
okay. We'll definitely figure it out.
>> Thank you. Wow.
>> I told you I was I was running around
here like a chicken with my head cut off
cuz I haven't closed my rings. I have
not showered. I was not able to get to
half of what I wanted to do today. But
>> I was at FedEx and they was moving so
[laughter] slow
and I live in a small area. I live in a
town. So like you it's the same people
all the time, you feel me? So like when
I got there I was like, "Oh, it's the
slow one."
And it's not it's not neurody
divergence. He just I don't mean like
he's just very casual, very odone is
ringing. Rang rang.
Um so someone asked, "Am I taking the
book on the Bible belt?" Yes. So the the
tour is in three parts. So I'm going to
be going to the southeast. I'm going to
be going to the uh Northeast as well and
then we'll see what happens. But I'm
with you, Brianna. Today was just a
weird I mean I the astrology girlies
would be like it's cuz the moon.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Energetically it's weird.
Speaking of if listeners if watchers
haven't watched the astrology episode of
Bad Faith with Issa Nagazak Zawa. She's
phenomenal. It caused quite the hub in
Bad Faith Patreon. I don't think there's
ever been more comments over on the
Patreon. [laughter]
Is this ever
>> a hubbub?
>> People are divi. I mean Amanda, you know
how people are. The the the the the
folks that listen to me for political
analysis were really sort of they were
they were miffed. I'll say they were
miffed at the idea that someone who they
trust and think is like credible and
respectable and grounded would even
entertain the kind of spirituality.
>> Can I speak to that?
Please do.
>> So this this is something that we really
do have to move past. And I want us to
think about the fact that anything that
colonizers
have rendered as unintellectual,
have rendered as
anti-faith, etc. ends up being attached
to the indigenous peoples that they were
colonizing. Like astrology is not solely
related to Romans or Greeks. This is
something that has existed in cultures
around this globe long before. And we
are seeing I just saw a leather map
today that was found. Hold on, let me I
just saw
um Hold on. I want to tell you about
this because I was so just like blown
away by this because we are so lied to
on such a consistent basis about the
amount of wisdom, the amount of
knowledge that took place before these
whites showed up. So a 300year-old
leather star map created by the Skitty
Pawnie. So that is an the indigenous
people of uh Indiana. We know this
because of Leslie Nope. um [laughter]
offers a rare glimpse into Native
American astronomy on the central
plains. And some people in here might be
like, well, that's astronomy. That's not
astrology. However, it all connects
because ultimately astrology is the
study of the planets as a telling of how
we are moving here on the earth. And I
am a very big believer that one of the
reasons why our resistance efforts end
up being thwarted so often is because we
have been thwarted from reconnecting to
knowledge that is beyond the classical
quote unquote concept of knowledge. We
actually need to move beyond those
barriers and get back to adding a
metaphysical element into our political
practice or else we're just mimicking
the same people that we keep trying to
fight. I I agree and I think that Issa
in particular is a very good vessel for
the for leftist to start to learn about
astrology because she is so grounded in
revolutionary practice and she is at at
at at bottom a very empathetic I mean
emotional intelligence off the roof. The
way my mom was like you need to make her
your best friend like she's just better
than my therapist. I was like she's
better than my therapist too. I didn't
you talk about astrology as it related
to like movements and nations because
that's a whole
>> that's a whole area of astrology. Like
these folks have been using astrology.
Ronald Reagan was Nancy Reagan was
running the White House with an
astrology.
>> She brought all of that up. Amanda, this
this whole episode is free so you can
listen to it wherever you get your
podcast or watch.
>> I am I am a subscriber to that faith
Patreon so I don't have to do that.
>> Thank you very much. But everyone I I I
wanted this one to be free and it's
free. So y'all
>> you want this particular one to be free?
>> Well, because
selfishly I this is where my like I I
find myself really wanting funner
episode. Like I want a break. I got to
just confess like sometimes I want a
break from hardcore politics,
>> you know? I I don't I don't like plan it
like whatever. Usually the just the
pacing of the episodes is what it is.
And if the interview happened to happen
before Thursday, it's free. And if it
happened to happen no on a Friday or a
Monday or Tuesday, you know, then it's
oh on a Friday, then it comes out on
Monday and it's paywalled. I don't
really plan it, but I was glad. I should
say I was glad this one landed the way
it did because
>> I didn't want to give anybody an excuse
not to watch it just because of their
ideological priors. I wanted
>> What did they feel was not real about
it? Like what did they feel was was not
I guess what I'm saying is what did they
feel that was like anti the you that
they have come to trust
>> because I mean you know how men can can
I just say it and also maybe we should
bring maybe we should bring Nathan
Robinson friend of the show is waiting
in the wings as well he is someone who
really embraces the idea of arts and
culture as being part of the left
movement
>> as you you can see from his set and
since I'm about to go in on men let's go
ahead and bring Nathan Robinson into the
room as well.
>> Hey
Have you met Amanda Seals? Do you know?
>> I have not met Nathan. Hello, Nathan.
>> So, Amanda, if you don't know, Nathan is
the publisher of what I believe to be
the best the [clears throat] me best
magazine on the left, current affairs
magazine, and it is a magazine that
embraces Oh, we have the same edition.
Exactly. [laughter]
>> This is the last one I actually had I
wrote something for.
>> That's why I keep this one up here. And
I like the cover a lot. It's iconic. Um,
but who, as you can tell,
>> I love a cat. So,
>> love a cat. And look at him. He he
clearly embraces a kind of whimsy in his
[snorts] personal presentation.
>> But for most people, they think of
politics as like the economist, you
know, red, black and white, like really
stayed like really serious. And I think
they have trouble with the idea of
someone who seems unserious because they
think astrology is unserious being able
to give them good advice about about the
real world.
>> Their version of politics is literally
determined for them by the same people
that have made this a Kraton barrel
beige world.
[laughter] The people who who try and
tell you that it's minimalist and it's
like no, it's devoid of culture.
>> It's devoid of vibes.
>> [laughter]
>> So men I was gonna say men in particular
and not all men but Nathan you can feel
free to weigh in. I find that men in
particular
have a real hostility toward a lot of
things that are sort of women coded and
astrology is one of those. If you think
about how differently we treat like a
husband who wants to watch the game and
the wife kind of has to just, you know,
go along with it because it's game night
versus a wife who might say, well, this
is the the season finale of some reality
TV show. Like those are treated as like,
oh well, the game is serious and the
reality TV is frivolous when they're
both frivolous. They're both
entertainment. Like yes, they're both
dumb. Like [laughter]
>> they're both creating to distract you
and bread and circuses. Like that's what
they're for.
>> Yeah. And I enjoy reality TV, but I'm
not going to say I'm not going to
pretend it's high art, but like also
don't pretend
>> it kind of is though.
>> The Lion's losing. [laughter]
>> Okay. But it also just it also just
ignores
the actual diversity that has been a
part of the leftist movement forever,
right? Like so you're telling me that
Diego and Freda are not like imperative
elements of the leftist movement and
they were consumate artists? I mean that
is not something that you can overlook.
And also I just think we we can't be in
the same mindset of only these people
are allowed to give points because we've
deemed them as the true version of and
it's not even based on values or
knowledge. Like if I'm an artist I have
and I have the same understanding of
theory. I have the same understanding of
pract of practice. I just have a
different way of thinking. I become an
asset because now we have an expanded
consciousness to work from. And so I,
you know, I
>> Yeah. Well, it depends.
>> I'm also a cancer with a cancer moon.
>> Okay. Well, Amanda, I apologize in
advance. There was a little bit of
cancer slander in this episode, but in
my defense,
>> men.
>> Men. It was because of men.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Cancer men. I love a Cancer woman.
>> Nathan, what's your sign?
>> Can I Oh, I don't know. Uh I uh uh but
>> when's your birthday?
>> Uh August 23rd.
>> Oh, a Virgo. Okay, continue.
>> Okay. I uh Oh, well, I just just one
little data point to kind of back up uh
what what Amanda's saying there is uh
this I I try to avoid criticizing too
much fellow leftists, but if you open up
Jacaban magazine, for example,
>> there's a kind of howling absence. And I
like a lot of what Jacabin publishes,
but it's more about what they don't
publish. And if you'll notice, there's
very little writing on um literature,
art, theater, um music. There's a little
bit of writing on film, um religion, and
spirituality. You know, these things are
just not really part of what they think
of as subjects for the left to discuss.
And that's a little weird, right? I
mean, they discuss, you know, the labor
movement and the workplace and they
discuss political organizing and
policing and and lots of important
things. But then there's this whole
other side of life which is which is
culture. And some leftists, and I I do
think of Jackaban as kind of like the
the paradigmatic example of this, just
aren't really interested in these things
um in in this side of life. Um, and that
that's kind of troubling to me.
>> Yeah. I don't think that's like I think
it's like counter to
the actual like what necessitates
looking at an entire working class,
right? And it leaves out a large swads
of people that are a part of not only
this politics and this thinking, but
also this actual space and place of
people. Like, you're leaving me out.
Don't leave me at
>> I agree. Look to this to this person's
point um who says Brian solidarity with
a vote for Siva is a vote for Matt with
a red beret. Simma has captured the
hearts and minds of many people because
he understands some good branding and
because the man goes hard for cats. He
loves animals. He's willing to show
diversity of his interest. Do I agree
with his political agenda? Absolutely
not. [laughter]
>> But you got to get points for style.
Even Even Derek, the style guy on
Twitter had to say today, "Look, I have
to I have to tip my hat to this tie he
wore to uh to vote today." He got the
endorsement of some like New York
animals group and he wore a tie that was
just all kitty cats on it.
>> Not kitty cat.
>> Kitty. [laughter]
>> Yes, kitty cat. I have a whole um I have
a whole section in the book about the
Panthers and I do an entire bit because
there is some standup that I trans
translated into the text and I I
basically reenact a Black Panther Party
meeting where the beret was decided on
and um how how was that how did they
decide on the beret? I'm curious. So the
real re the real reason why the beret
was decided on was because it was
continuing the presence of like the for
the French foreign legion and like there
were there the the beret had become
associated with organized resistance.
However, in my mind that's not how it
happened. And so I do a whole bit that a
Frenchman showed up to a meeting and was
like, I think that you guys should do
something different. [laughter] Um, you
know, to just kind of like add to the
pizzazz. And that is actually how they
became aware. [laughter]
>> You guys wanted to get my wear out of
this $15 hat because I think it's
>> You could rock that. You You could rock
that.
>> When when the Bernie campaign was
happening in 2020, I pitched us having
little red beret. Sorry. Little red
handkerchiefs because I felt like
>> Yeah. Like little like like little neck
like little neck scarves because hear me
out. There's a story about the is it the
bacon rebellion that says there were it
was like a coal mine and there were
there were everyone was paid in script
and it was a company town and the
conditions were really terrible and they
had white American workers, they had
black American workers and then they had
white immigrant workers and they housed
them differently, paid them differently
and pit them all against each other. But
then there was this big rebellion and
they were like, "No, screw this noise.
We're all going to glom together." And
part of the way they showed they
identified with each other were were
these red handkerchiefs. And the story
is maybe apocryphal, but some think
that's where the term redneck came from
in the first place. So you're taking
what we think of as a term of like
that's coded for white rural ignorant
back attitude, whatever, and say, "No,
no, no. This was actually originally a
term about crosscl class and c uh cross
uh national and crossracial solidarity.
We're going to take that appropriate as
part of our campaign and also it's a
clothing item that it's cheap to
manufacture, cheap to buy and that you
can wear with all items of clothing
without committing to like a whole
t-shirt or something.
>> Yeah.
>> And and you can tie it to your purse and
people in the world can know, hey, I'm
with this movement. But nobody listened
to me.
>> [laughter]
>> You know, Zoran did bandanas.
>> Did he?
>> Zoran Zoran did yellow bandanas with
pigeons and hot dogs and taxis on them.
And
>> I did see those. I did.
>> Everyone wanted the the Zoron bandanas.
And you know that's the difference.
>> It's smart. Like you have to normalize
the idea that you're not alone. So much
of this stuff is a collective action
problem. You need to be seeing out in
the world embracing the ideology.
>> That's what the kia is. That's what the
keier has become because
>> people always say to me, "I see you.
Thank you for wearing your cafe." Like
all the time like we have moments in,
you know, whether it's in the mall or in
in a airport or the grocery store. And I
think that to your point it's and it's a
very I remember actually Alice Walker
saying that she had become so deeply
vested in the Palestine movement that
she gave herself a stroke
>> and she was like I had to figure out
like how to still support Palestine but
in a way that's not going to kill me.
And so she was like so I wear a keffia
every day everywhere I go. And she was
like, "Of course, it's, you know, not
the same effort as I was giving before,
but I it's still me showing solidarity
in any space." And she was like,
"That's, you know, so that's her." She
was like, "That's where I'm at now with
it now." She was also on a boat that got
bomb. So, it's like, okay, we, you know,
>> yeah,
>> I I love that story. I I was not
familiar with that, but that totally
resonates with me. I want to just shout
out. Also, I want to say, Amanda, you've
been here for an hour. I don't want to
keep you all night. You're welcome to
stay, but I want [laughter]
before you go out, if you go, I want to
make sure I read that Ju Guu says that
she tips her beret to us fine ladies and
also that uh Brent said hi to the both
of us that were the goats and with good
hearts. We appreciate the both of you
and these other super stickers without
any
>> super good supporting.
>> Yes, everyone. The the the crew is
great. The crew is great. But Amanda,
before you go, I had this queue up.
>> Or you don't have to go. I'm not kicking
you out. I just want I didn't see
>> Oh, no. I want to I want to see a Did
you Did you actually see it?
>> See what this?
>> Oh, no. Not this. Oh god.
>> Oh, I've seen it. But I think the world
needs to see it. [laughter]
>> To correct the record if you give you a
chance to to correct the record.
>> Oh my god. Why are the feds hating on
you right now? Oh my god. Give you a
chance to
for real.
>> Give you a chance to correct the record
if you didn't mean to say something like
you said diversity can also be a
weakness. What did you mean by that?
>> Diversity can be a weakness uh if you
have antipathy among groups. Jonathan,
uh if you have uh racism, [laughter]
>> give you a
>> I'm Eugene.
>> Sorry, I thought I have a longer version
of it. That's my bad.
>> But that's all we needed to see.
>> I'm Eugene.
>> That's all we needed to see.
>> Sent me. Okay.
>> With a flip of the afro. Just a quick
flick. I'm Eugene. [laughter]
>> Cuz like him and Kart are not even
remotely
similar. [snorts]
>> Anyh who,
>> no. No.
>> What was he even trying to say, you
guys? Like, I honestly was It was so
nonsensical. But I don't even know what
he was actually trying to convey.
>> I I I don't think he knew either. That's
why I was going to I was going to go do
the the longer version.
>> Diversity is our strength, but uh it can
also be a weakness. So, you have to work
very very hard uh to make sure you're
always keeping people united.
>> Is you said diversity can also be a
weakness. What did you mean by that?
Diversity can be a weakness uh if you
have antipathy among groups Jonathan uh
if you have uh racism or anti-semitism
etc. uh so uh then you'd have friction
right which we have had in New York
>> so there is a charitable way to
>> so what he's saying I guess is
>> what he's trying to say
>> racism is bad but he's calling that a
weakness of diversity that's okay like
diversity isn't a weakness there's
antipy between groups meaning like the
racism is the problem not the diversity
you know it's diversity's fault in The
same way that it's my fault for getting
punched in the face because I have a
face.
>> Yes. [laughter]
>> GOD DANG IT, BRIANA. WHY WOULD YOU SHOW
UP HERE with your face? [laughter]
You knew people was going to be here
with fists and you gonna walk up in here
with your face. [laughter]
>> It's called the stop hitting yourself
defense of puffer bigots.
>> Wow. But that Okay. But to for him to
say that on national television
means that like this is a rhetoric that
he's like super comfortable engaging in
all the time.
>> Yeah. I think and this will maybe brings
us back to the articles that I I teed up
this hour with and what I brought Nathan
to to speak with in more detail because
he just wrote a piece critiquing these
kinds of pieces in current affairs
magazine. But it's to me it's endemic of
the liberals
deciding that their way through the Mum
Donnie and kind of left successes of the
moment is to be the adults in the room
who are willing to throw identity
politics under the bus, but they don't
really have an understanding of a kind
of a weaponized identity politics that
was very superficial that was bad for
liberals versus just abandoning the
substantive in interests of historical
minorities like a historically
marginalized group. So, he's clearly
been in some like thirdway chat about
how we're not doing diversity politics
anymore and that um DEI was bad for
Dems. So, that's why that's my theory as
to why he's thinking diversity is a
weakness. He's being like DEI was a
problem for Dems,
but it came out as uh diversity bad
because it causes friction. And
interestingly all that whole talking
point of diversity is a weakness I mean
is directly lift lifted from Tucker
Carlson and the white nationalist.
Tucker Carson gave a big monologue like
in 2022 called diverse something like
diversity is not a strength it's a
weakness and his whole argument is uh a
a country needs to cohhere it needs to
have a coherent national culture so you
could pursue your national project and
meaning essentially like a country is
stronger if it's a single race and uh
you know so so Cuomo there and and the
liberals who are ditching what they
consider to be ditching ident bad
pernitious identity politics uh really
just end up spouting all of the rhetoric
of the white nationalist right uh who
use this whole diversity as a weakness
thing. I mean that that's that's
straight out of Tucker Carson and the
far right.
>> I would also add to circle all the way
back to what Briana was saying before
you brought me on. Briana, you were
talking about this very uh obvious shift
by the Dems to be like, "This is we're
we're alpha. We're dudes. We're we're
gonna we're gonna get the dudes, right?"
When I was like pitching I was pitching
a show um
>> I was pitching a show in LA in like
2023. And so you get these like weekly
pitches um like pitch sheets that
basically tell you like this is what
this network is looking for, this is
what that network is looking for. And I
will never forget when my agent was like
so the real the real vibe right now is
loud male. And I was like
>> right [laughter] now
>> what does that even mean? And she was
like you know shows like Dave, you know,
just like loud male, you know what I
[laughter] mean? And I was like I
genuinely am like I don't understand
what you mean. But that is what the Dems
are doing. Like it is that it's loud
male. And you know, I'm always going to
bring Kla Harris's name into it.
[laughter] She is now doing loud male.
You got a cursing like a sailor now.
Yeah. Right.
>> Like the posture. You're watching all of
them shift posture. It's And they're
shifting posture to Tucker Carlson, I
think, because
>> he has leaned a little.
I mean, how do you even He was so It's
basically he did the Michael Jackson
lean in Smooth Criminal. Like that's how
far right he has always been. So he's
essentially just like standing up
straight now. Um but they are like, "Oh,
we can GET THE ONES LIKE HIM, so we need
to like lean into him." And it's
disgusting to watch. It really is.
I'm glad you teed up like that, Amanda,
because this is I think the the central
tension of what's going on here is that
one team is claiming, okay, there's
there's a broad agreement that obviously
you got to pull some people back into
the coalition of the Democrats to win.
My audience knows about the Democrat,
but just argument that's being happening
right now. The the the Democrats are in
turmoil and they're saying we got to
bring people back in the coalition. And
one camp is saying we do so by moving to
the right and becoming some version of
uh a Republican, moving to the right on
immigration, adopting a kind of economic
populism. Even Ezra Klein will admit to
doing that, but he'll only take that so
far. And then there's the left that
says, well, economic populism isn't the
way it is is in fact the way, but you
don't have to move so to the right on
all of these cultural issues. And what
Bernie Sanders says in the New York
magazine piece uh abundance versus uh
socialism is that look, you can just say
economic populism and then people don't
pay that much attention. They just kind
of deprioritize the cultural stuff and
it doesn't matter if they disagree with
you, but you don't have to say I don't
like exgroup anymore because you're
never going to convincingly well maybe
some people are actually racist and
bigots, but you're never going to
convincingly out bigot the right. So
it's a feudal effort. Besides which,
that's not what really this is about.
But the abundance people are fully
saying, "No, no, no. We've got to run
more anti-choice candidates, and we have
to reverse ourselves on some of these
policies." Nathan, you wrote this piece.
The case for centism does not hold up.
Sorry. I'm sure it looks beautiful.
>> I print it out, too.
>> Oh, here we go.
>> Apologies to the trees. I print
everything out.
>> No, it's in the midst of whatever you're
about to do, will you also help for me?
because my ignorance is showing here.
Help me land who these abundance people
are because this is the first
>> they're not anybody. You you you're
completely correct not to know any of
these people cuz they're nobody. It's
like uh I mean essentially like Ezra
Klene, the New York Time thought leader
of the Democratic Party uh and and a
writer at the Atlantic uh Thompson uh
wrote a Derek Thompson wrote a book
which is now a best has been a
bestseller for weeks and weeks called
abundance. And they they essentially
they had both written articles for their
respective publications that both made
some version of the same argument. The
argument they made was uh that the you
know Democrats are searching for their
path back to power. The agenda they need
is this thing called abundance which
sounds very vague and confusing. Um, and
essentially when you dig into what they
mean by it, they basically mean um
deregulation a little bit, but but like
Yimi, the idea of building lots of
houses um and uh and ditching, you know,
the bad identity politics and uh and
that's kind of what they're
>> capitalism.
>> Yeah. The nice capitalism.
>> So neoliberalism. Okay. Okay.
>> Well, yes. No.
So, and then it comes back and you're
like, "Wait, isn't this just
neoliberalism again?" And they go, "No,
well, no, no, no, it's not
neoliberalism. Uh, this is abundance."
Uh, it's it's totally different, but
it's just Yeah. old what? Old wine.
>> Trippy about that, you guys. They're
doing the they're doing the the language
flip thing that these Republicans have
become so gifted at with woke, with DT
uh with DEI, with I almost said DTF. DT
dei with um you know critical race
theory because the concept of abundance
>> well
it is it is in direct it is in direct
>> arguing it is in direct conflict with
the true scarcity that capitalism
causes. So they're literally just trying
to take this concept of abundance and
call it something else. It's very the
it's very the Kardashians making
literally not mean literally which
drives me [laughter]
and like I can't remember if it was
Mariam Webster or somebody put that in
the actual dictionary that there's
another version of literally of
literally other than literally
[laughter] but that is frightening to me
namely because
they're just so far away from where I
think people actually think they are.
And I think that in maybe as soon as 10
years, we should all come back here and
talk about the time when we were on here
talking about the Democrats like they
would continue to exist. [laughter] So
let's just make that date. This is So
Amanda, we if you want to, we can come
back to this like sort of central
tension that emerged during our kind of
organizing meeting that we were both a
part of that we both have alluded to
earlier in this conversation where
Amanda and I emerged as kind of very
loud
Um, [laughter]
and you didn't know that we were
positioned inadvertently at opposite
ends of the room. So, there was
literally like there was no escaping us.
And we just pingponged
back and forth. They got good cop bad.
Well, we don't do it's a cab all day.
So, they they got they got nice high
pitch voice black women and they
[clears throat] got deep voice black
woman. And [laughter]
was that I know they were so tired of
us. I know they were so tired of us. But
there this this division emerged between
a more reformist f everyone in there was
ideologically aligned but it was like a
methodological difference of more
reformist versus more revolutionary. But
for if if people want a good the a good
faith like unbiased
uh the not even good faith like the way
the abundance would probably want
themselves described because the New
York Magic was very like I would argue
pro-abundance.
Uh this is how they characterize it.
After describing on the left what's
going on with Bernie and Zuron and AOC,
which I don't have to read out loud
because we all understand the appeal of
that stuff. They say the third force in
American politics is the abundance
movement, which is exciting not to the
general public, [laughter] but to the
>> words
[laughter]
to the political class and wonk and
intelligencia popularized by the book of
the same name. Wonk like you know
>> into the details. Yeah. Popularized by
the book of the same name by Ezra Klein
and Derek Thompson. It argues that the
United States has grown stagnant and
unaffordable thanks to regulatory
absurdities, nimi homeowners,
homeowners, infrastructure blocking
environmentalists, and other obstacles
to quote a liberalism that builds. Like
the populists on the left, abundance
partisans argue the system is broken.
Yet their attitude towards Silicon
Valley is more tech utopian than anti-
monopolistic and the targets of their
critiques tend not to be billionaires
but others in the Democratic coalition
which has led to a civil war between
them and the Bernie Zoron AOC faction.
The term abundance and anti-oligarchy
are too narrow to encompass all the
people now associated with each camp,
but they have come to represent a
feverish grasp for the steering wheel as
the party searches for direction.
>> So this is sounds like a couple of guys
trying to make fetch happen. That's
literally
>> 100%. [laughter] I've said that exact
thing so many times. They're trying to
make abundance happen and there's a lot
of money behind this. So OB Obama is
talking about abundance. Um you you
every every um every other elected
representative who goes on POS America
just throws the word abundance in
conversation.
>> They sat around a table and they came up
with this and now we're supposed to just
go along with it
>> 100%. And they had a conference, the
abundance people had a conference
called, sorry I got like too many sheets
of paper called the decide uh the
welcome pack a couple of months ago in
the fall and they issued this paper
called deciding to win which is this
59page memo analyzing what the next step
should be. And of course their next
steps are all the kind of milk to like
they they're like they're they're
allowing a little bit on the fringes the
idea that yeah economic populism is
popular but they notably omit those big
tent policies that are very popular like
actually taxing the rich. So, you want
to do economic populism, but um okay,
fine. We'll concede to a $15 minimum
wage 10 years after it should have been
a $25 minimum wage and we're going to
know that the Democrats are never going
to pass it for the same reason that
Biden never passed it with his trifecta
and we're going to say that this means
we're doing populism now. Is that fair?
Is that fair, Nathan? Would you how do
you how do you address the case for
centism
in your takedown piece
filed today that came out today?
>> Uh it did come it did come out today. I
uh that that interestingly with that
deciding to win report because uh Ross
Daet published a there was two there's
two pieces in the New York Times that I
responded to. One is the New York Times
published this piece that says you know
just by the editorial board as a whole
that says uh moderate candidates tend to
win. they have an advantage. Um, and uh,
the Democrats generally just need to,
you know, abandon all the bad identity
politics stuff and move to the center.
And then Ross Det published his own
column arguing basically the same thing.
And he said, you know, it's [snorts] so
obvious that Kla Harris lost because she
was too left-wing. And if you don't
believe me, read this uh, read this
report. Well, interestingly, if you do
read the report, I I mean, I guess he
didn't expect anyone to actually click
on it or or click through it. I mean,
it's true that it kind of recommends
that, but what one of the things that's
interesting is is, as you've hinted
there, they basic the evidence that like
that Bernie Sanders politics are
incredibly popular is by now so beyond
dispute that they essentially have to
concede this point. Um, I mean, we've
been arguing, we on the left have been
arguing that Bernie for 10 years now,
current affairs just had its 10 year
anniversary and our like one of our
first articles was like, you need to
nominate Bernie Sanders if you're going
to win. This is the politics that can
defeat the far right. So, we've been
banging this drum for 10 years. And the
crazy thing about that report is that
ultimately it doesn't show that uh this
that housing deregulation is like the uh
center of an agenda that can win. In
fact, they say in it like the Bernie
Sanders, Zaron Mandani, AOC um you know,
relentless focus on improving people's
basic economic circumstances
um is is the way to go. They say in fact
the template is Bernie Bernie 2016 and
they they also say the template is Obama
2008, you know, even though those are
quite different campaigns. Um, but it's
remarkable to me how much they concede.
And then I went into the evidence that
the New York Times produces that
moderate candidates um do better. Well,
that that it turns out they just
basically uh put in fraudulent numbers.
There's a
>> there's a political scientist, Adam Bur,
who who dived into how they do this and
essentially they [snorts] they rigged
the statistics to prove something that
was actually false. Uh, I mean, he he
pretty convincingly shows that basically
they just proved that people with super
PAC money win elections and people who
are incumbents. Um, and they concluded
instead because those people tend to be
moderates, right? Because there are a
lot of incumbents who are moderates.
They're like, "Oh, no, moderates win.
It's it's because they're moderates."
Well, you know, Bara shows actually they
haven't proved it at all. So, you know,
there there's these two articles that
are making this case and and neither of
them provide any, you know, actual
strong evidence. And in fact, if you
dive into the evidence they do provide
in the case of this report, um it
basically admits that the opposite is
true.
>> Yeah. Let let me tell you, let me read a
little bit if you can like hold on to
your lunch or your dinner, whatever meal
you've last eaten while I get through
this because it is vomit inducing. This
is from Ezra Klein's piece uh titled
This is the way you beat Trump and
Trumpism. He says, "One worry I have
about Democrat
>> Wait, when was this? When was this?"
>> Uh, this came out November 2nd, a couple
days ago. He says, "One worry I have
about Democrats right now is that they
do not want to confront how much of the
country disagrees with them. Polls show
that the percentage of voters saying the
Democratic party is too liberal
increased sharply between 2012 and 2024.
The percentage of voters saying the
Republican party is too conservative
fell during that same period. Even the
violence and corruption of Trump's
second administration have not fully
closed the gap. Now, he attributes I I
circled this and said, "You're right.
The party is too liberal. It's not the
same thing as being too left." Now, this
is the part that's really gonna make you
want to hurl. I couldn't believe I could
not believe this. I could not believe
this. He says,
[snorts]
"Sorry, where's the bit about us being
too black?" Oh, here it is. Here it is.
He says, "Okay, from 2012 to 2024,
Democrats move sharply left on virtually
every issue."
Hey, remember when the left in the in
the room with us?
>> Okay. Okay. Okay. All right. Here's
here's how this is what he says. They
often did so arguing that they were
finally representing communities that
had long suffered from too little
representation. This is what they were
told to do by the online voices and
professional groups that claimed to
represent these communities.
>> But it went wrong. Democrats became more
uncompromising on immigration and lost
support among Hispanic voters. They
moved left on guns and student loans and
climate and lost ground with young
voters. They moved left on race and lost
ground with black voters. They moved
left on race.
>> What? [laughter] What? What does that
even mean?
>> Well, he doesn't substantiate any of
this any of this.
>> They move left on economics.
Is the economics in the room with us?
Exactly. They moved left of economics
and lost ground with working class
voters.
The only major group I agree with the
dog. The only major group in which
Democrats saw improvement across the
whole 12-year period was college
educated white voters. Now, now group
team panel.
>> Oh my god.
>> What do you think's going on here? I
turn it over to you.
>> Oh, I mean, you know, there's a version
of this. Ezra Cly is not the only one
saying this. I mean, I I hear it over
and over. essentially essentially like
it seems to me like the response to the
abysmal failures of the Hillary Clinton
campaign in 2016. Joe Biden squeaked in
in 2020. People still don't realize how
narrow it was and how it occurred in
large part because Trump was killing his
own voters. Um and then Kamla and then
the disaster of the Biden presidency
which became hugely unpopular which we
on the left were warning it would be. We
literally published an article the day
uh I think Joe Biden was inaugurated
saying like Trump is going to be back in
four years because this is going to be a
disastrous presidency and then the
disaster of the Kla Harris campaign. um
which we know exactly what happened
there, which is she started off sounding
progressive and her numbers went up and
then um her uh crypto lobbyist
brother-in-law uh or her Uber lobbyist
brother-in-law and the crypto lobby got
to her and she started waffling more and
then you saw her poll numbers tank as
the election became closer and closer
and she started talking about the
importance of fossil fuels and she
wouldn't say anything on Gaza other than
it's very sad. So we [snorts] all know
what happened there which is that
leftists we in if you go back and read
the history of current affairs we're
warning at every turn Hillary Clinton's
a terrible candidate Joe Biden's a
terrible candidate Kla Harris is a
terrible candidate you need Bernie style
populism and then you know our theory is
entirely vindicated here the response to
this is to rewrite history is to just go
back and go like the Democrats did
leftism and it failed.
>> You know why though? [laughter]
>> You know what? Because
>> y
>> these people are it's not that they're
Republicans or Democrats or they're
Zionists.
That's really what this really is.
They're Zionists. So it's the tree and
the roots, right? Like the Democrat
Republican part of this is a branches,
but at the end of the day, they're
grounded in Zionism as a political
ideology and mindset that essent that is
racist by nature.
and that ultimately does not see things
through an honest lens. Like it just
does. It can't even exist in that way.
And so what we're actually what I think
we're actually seeing is the continued
bubbling up of Zionism that is going to
end up thwarting it's actually going to
end up bringing all of them together
because there is not a
dis there isn't a definition there isn't
anything defining between their Zionism
there their their republicanism and and
Democratism was really the these are all
just like masks that they're wearing in
the process of engaging in an actual
deeper effort that is going on. And I
think for what it's worth, that hasn't
that analysis hasn't really been
happening as I feel like that I feel
like particularly as a black person who
was watching more mainstream political
discussion, there was never any
whatsoever acknowledgment that Zionism
played any role in any of this at any
time.
>> And there still isn't. There's still
>> no
>> and there and there's almost no
acknowledgement of the role that
Zionism and Zoron's pro Palestinian
advocacy played in his race toward the
end there's this very ironic thing
speaking of flipping the words that was
happening where once Cuomo realized how
he was being damaged by his association
with Israel and Netanyahu being
Netanyahu's lawyer and the like that he
started saying well why is this race a
referendum on Israel I'm running for
mayor of New York which of course is
Zoron was saying in the beginning when
Cuomo's team tried to make this a refer
referendum on Israel because he thought
it was going to endure to his benefit.
So, I think you're right, Amanda, and I
want you to get in here too, Nathan,
that there is a the whole abundance
effort is to try to act as though you
agree with some aspects of what is
popular about Zoron, whether it's the
aesthetic or at least the narrow
economic populism without touching any
of the core values of the establishment,
which include a commitment to Israel and
our imperialism as a country. Yes.
>> And also it's relatedly our commitment
to the corporate elite. Y I say
relatedly because the weapons industry
which is the backbone of the American
economy and our interventionist efforts
of course in lock step as is the um
fossil fuel industry versus the
environment long-term environmental
goals and
uh uh public health goals that are
associated with environmental harms.
Which is why when I when I try to
explain to people what abundance is when
it boiled down one of the things in the
book which I in fact did read uh is that
they tee up this idea that housing is
being curtailed by needless regulation
and they do this thing where they mostly
don't get specific about which
regulations they're talking about
because when they do it gives the whole
game away and in this one moment they're
talking about the need for housing in
California and they say look if you
insist that we build housing that isn't
going to make the kids that live in the
housing sick we're going to have less
housing. So, you got to let us build
housing that doesn't have the air
filters that are going to keep kids from
having asthma.
>> Yeah. Well, and uh um one of Matt
Elazius's big things is we should have
uh we should be allowed to build
apartments without windows. Um,
[laughter]
>> so
and look, even if you if you believe
that there was a kind of a pragmatic
argument where it's better to live in a
house without windows than under a
bridge, they're really presuming they're
they're asking you to presume that the
barrier to having housing supply is
building windows and having ventilation
and not building, you know, on a highway
as opposed to uh venture capital firms
buying up empty uh houses and leaving
them empty. Or uh these private partner
public uh partnerships that take public
money to build luxury housing and then
create a few low-income units that you
have to enter through a back door so the
rich people don't see the low-income
people entering the housing and having
destroyed a bunch of dense public
housing and able to build that in the
first place. All of those kinds of
things. Sorry, Nathan, I see you wanted
to get in here.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Or just the fact that wealth
is highly concentrated, you know, just
the fact [laughter] that some people are
poor while other people are very very
very rich.
>> That's my brother. Shout out to my
brother in the comment section. I just
pulled it up because it was a good
comment. Lol. [laughter]
>> Hey bro.
>> I mean it is certainly true that there
is uh a real effort to tell the story of
2024 without talking about Palestine. Uh
which you can't really do. uh the Biden
administration was responsible for a
genocide and that's the basic fact you
know this uh in in 1984 he he tries to
cling to the basic truth that 2 plus 2
equals 4. Well, the truth of like of
trying to remember uh what happened over
the last few years is to cling to the
basic fact that the administration the
US government was perpetrating a
genocide. Right? That is the basic core
most important fact of the last couple
of years. And you've got to [laughter]
and you've got to build all of your
analysis around that.
>> Yes. And and so for Ezra Klein to write
a column where he talks about like the
Democrats, you know, oh, they moved left
on this issue, they moved left on this
issue, but not discuss, you know, this
this massive overarching issue, which
was the worst human rights crisis of our
time. And this was the thing that
disgusted absolutely disgusted a huge
part of the Democratic base. Um I I
believe they have pretty convincing
analyses showing that Kamala Harris lost
directly because of this in that if she
had uh done what the p the very taken
the very very modest steps that
Palestine activists were asking her to
take um but which was things like you
know even symbolic things like letting a
Palestinian speak at the at the DNC um
and
>> just optics
>> just really just optic things that she
wouldn't even do she wouldn't let go of
her commitment to Israel and she lost
the election accordingly. Well, I mean,
that's the story of what happened in
2024.
And so really, all of this, you know,
abundance versus socialism stuff is a
total distraction from the actual core
story of 2024, which is that the Biden
administration perpetrated, didn't
support, but essentially perpetrated a
>> made lies up to make it happen. So, that
is definitely perpetrating. Um, yeah,
they perpetrated their genocide. It's
their genocide. I'm right. I actually my
next American genocide. Um, because it's
about, you know, how this is not really
an Israeli I mean, it is an Israeli
crime, but it's an American crime.
>> So, this is a question I have for you
guys because my ramen is about to
arrive.
>> Okay.
>> Go, please.
So,
I have noticed in the past three days an
abundance
>> abundance
>> of Damn it, that wasn't even on purpose.
>> An abundance [laughter]
of Sudan
presence on my timeline. So, at first I
was like, "Oh, wow." Like, I'm glad to
see this.
>> Yeah.
>> And then I remembered though where I'm
at. I'm in the metaverse. So whenever
the algorithm does a a big switch,
there's something behind that. And uh I
also saw Palestinian
influencers and voices and journalists
doing videos specifically about Sudan
and folks that I rarely see speak
English, speaking English in their
videos. And so I was curious what you
guys think could be attributing to that
because then I also saw that there's the
info wars that begun where you're seeing
you know American uh diplomats and
people
uh speaking who was the person I it was
I think it was a UN person who are all
of a sudden like Sudan is crazy what's
going on in Sudan. And you're like, "But
y'all never cared about Sudan." So like,
what's what's actually happening?
Curious if you guys have any theories.
>> You can go first if you want to, Nathan.
I I have
>> Well, I mean, I don't I don't actually
know uh what's uh uh you know, what
forces are operating in the background.
I mean, I will say that for the entire
duration of the Gaza genocide, there
have been efforts, constant constant
efforts at every level of the United
States government and it's bipartisan
and it's corporate to do everything
possible to get people to pay attention
to something else. And so even if it's
genuine events on the ground that are,
you know, that are that are real, it's
not it's not that that, you know, it's
not to negate or deny the reality of the
of the suffering of people in in Sudan.
Um, it creates an opportunity that is
seized upon by many actors who have been
looking for some way to get us to talk
about anything other than the
destruction of Gaza. So, it's not
surprising that there are many many
people who, you know, see that see that
genocide as essentially an opportunity
um to to distract us and and and you're
right, Amanda. Of course, they don't
care about uh people of Sudan,
obviously. Um um but they they do want
something. I mean, I mean, this is
consistent. It's not just Sudan.
Obviously, you know, this is the
consistent tactic of the apologists of
US empire, which is to find the crimes
of other actors and point to them and
get us to pay attention to uh Putin's
repression or a repression in Iran or or
or China or Venezuela or North Korea,
you know, find anything other than the
crimes that we are perpetrating and tell
us look at that, not at this.
>> That's exactly what I was going to say.
oftentimes if you look at the accounts
that are saying why aren't you posting
about Sudan and then you Google like you
search Sudan in their own post they've
never mentioned it before that
>> and it's tough because I do frankly
think that there is an asymmetry between
how much attention is there different
conflicts that is related to yes
anti-black racism and
>> I think I think that is true and the
black person in me is very vulnerable
frankly to that particular kind of
attack I do I did put out feelers to try
to get some good guests to come on to
talk about Sudan because I do think it's
important to cover. But I also think
that the people who are pointing fingers
in that direction are doing so in bad
faith. Yeah. And in particular because
there are stories right now, I was
trying to pull one up while you guys
were talking, but I couldn't find one in
time about how social media posts are be
about Gaza are being deleted and also
the timeline is very much deemphasizing
anything having to do with Gaza. Well,
all the journalists are gone as well,
right? So, that was a big, not all, but
a lot, I mean, an insane amount. And,
you know, a lot of the reason why we
weren't getting any coverage about Sudan
was because there wasn't people there
weren't people on the ground that had
the same capability as getting the story
out um in by nature of, you know,
internet blackouts and technology, etc.,
etc. So there's like a whole poetry
movement that is aligned with resistance
in Sudan that actually does very much
work with the digital space and um
there's a film about it called Sud
remember remember me Sudan that speaks
to this. However, when I see what's
happening right now, it's it's
it's a catch 22 because on one hand I'm
like I'm very glad that this is being um
you know that this is being amplified. I
also know there will be no genuine
efforts done to stop it.
>> I don't by any means expect any efforts
to be done. I mean, you have the head of
the RSF like casually sitting in the
Waldo Historia in Paris and he gets run
up on with cameras with phones by Sudin
who are like, "What the heck are y'all
doing here? Like, this is not cool." and
they're like,
"Hey," because they're impervious. For
whatever reason, they are in a western
country feeling impervious. And so, at
the same time, I find myself also not
knowing what's going on in Palestine for
the first time in two and a half years.
>> I don't
>> know in the same way that I did.
Not to mention, I think post ceasefire,
the corporate media went into full full
court press of why aren't you grateful
that a ceasefire has happened and Dana
Bash had Deborah Messing on to bring the
conversation back full circle to her.
>> Yeah. To do a to like ask to interview
her very seriously like well like you've
been a staunch advocate for Israel
throughout like and people have been
calling for a ceasefire and your
mentions like have you seen people
celebrating the ceasefire? She's like,
"No, I that's not it's how hypocritical
of them not to be celebrating a
ceasefire." And meanwhile, obviously, we
all know that the killing hasn't
stopped. There was that horrible image
of what looked like a little mini
nuclear bomb going off um with the radio
spreading out in Gaza just yesterday, I
believe. Um dozens killed on a on a
daily basis. Uh, I'm going to have later
in the week an interview with the
journalist who recorded that really
gling footage of being chased, an
American journalist being chased by
settlers in the West Bank, narrowly
escaping into his car before the
settlers move on and bash older
Palestinian woman over the head
>> with an implement. Um, that's what we
know is ongoing during the so-called
ceasefire, but that's not what the
mainstream news is very coordinated
response to the ceasefire news was. So,
it felt it feels to me like they said,
"We've got a ceasefire on paper. or
we're going to stop covering it. We're
going to use that as a justification to
suppress or like a cover for suppressing
the news on social media because it
seems like well maybe things just died
down.
>> Yeah.
>> And then we'll divert the audience and
we're going to continue to do what we're
doing. Um, and it's diabolical.
And it also just makes me say
we can't when we see these things like
we can't just go along with it, you
know, like it has we have to like call
it, amplify it, all the things. And um I
don't know if you
Damn, I lost my train of thought. There
was something I was going to tell you
before I go. talk amongst yourselves.
>> Um, happily, I just wanna shout out
this Simma tweet where he is Batman
style calling his supporters. [laughter]
I
>> God, there is something so likable about
him despite the fact that he's a uh
fraudster and a fascist thug.
>> 100%. But my god, the branding. Also,
you should have seen me on Halloween. I
was such a menace. People were trying to
introduce themselves to me like an
actuality and I was like I'M CURTIS
LEEWA WHO'S GOT A CAT. [laughter]
I WAS SHOT FIVE THIS I WAS WHERE'S
WHERE'S does anyone know where THE
NAPKINS ARE? I'LL TELL you about the
napkins. I need a lot of napkins AND I
WAS SHOT FIVE TIMES WHEN I GOT INTO A
NEW YORK City taxi cab.
>> You really embraced the roll there all
night. You must [laughter]
>> very method of you. I appreciate that as
a
>> I was truly insufferable. I Yeah, it
sounds great.
>> Yes. Also, I go ahead and read some of
these off as well while Amanda's
thinking. I'm very bad at doing this. Uh
to BJG, Amanda
and Nathan, many hearts. Thank you,
Kimmy. Uh Jimbo, wow, didn't have Bri
being a sleep on on my 2025 card.
To be clear, I'm just
>> an appreciator of the aesthetic.
>> Oh, I got it. I remember.
>> Yes.
>> Go for it.
Karen.
>> Oh,
[sighs and gasps]
[laughter]
Karen Jean Pierre.
I saw her do a really Oh, she was on
>> Lean.
>> She She was on with Lean uh
>> Van
>> Van Van Lean Jr.
So now they're all doing So how I'm
wondering how Van Lean's podcast got
into like the the Dem
circuit. Um I I think what's happening
is that they they they're all looking
for black voters. I think first of all,
two things are happening. They they to
your point, they want big male energy.
Okay. They also want they all
>> loud mail.
>> Loud mail. Sorry. They they feel
although obviously Lindsay is on that
show as well, but I don't mean to
invisibleize. But it's I mean
>> but they also want black votes. They
know all especially all the white
candidates know that they can't get
Bernied, you know, with news articles
that say that they can't win the black
vote. Like Buddha Judge can't win the
black vote. And then they also think
racistly that they're going to have easy
interviews on black shows.
>> And Van said this after the the
disastrous Gavin News article interview
>> that he thought that Gavin thought that
it was going to be a cakewalk. He
thought they were gonna talk about like
what's your favorite car and stuff like
that.
>> Yeah. What's your what's your favorite
90s hiphop album?
>> You ever [laughter] date a black girl?
Did you ever date a black girl?
>> Okay. Is this is this uh is this the new
Paul Thomas Anderson movie? Have
[laughter] you ever dated a black girl?
Wait, have you have you seen it yet?
Have you seen One Battle Again and
again? Because that's literally a line
from the movie.
>> Do you like Black Girls with Tiana?
>> I saw it and was like, "Do not go waste
your money and see that. doing doing
goody dance. [laughter]
>> Mom is right. Mom is right. I had Van on
to talk about it and that was the issue
like they they fetish they fetishize
black women and act like we're supposed
to be very impressed that
some people in the movie want to screw
black girls and they keep they literally
that's a line of dialogue. Do you like
black girls? Yeah, I like black girls. I
can't get enough of them. I like black
girls. And it's it's so cringe. It is
the only time the only time in my entire
life I've genuinely considered getting
up and walking out of a movie. Oh,
>> really? You've never gotten up and
walked out?
>> No, cuz I like bad stuff. I like to hate
on stuff. I like to talk about stuff
that I hate. Like I'm a personal hater.
[laughter]
>> This was like
this was like I can't enjoy this. And
but for the fact that I was there on a
date,
>> I I don't know that I would have like
stay sat in my seat.
>> You went to go see that movie on a date?
>> I didn't pick it. Yes, it was.
>> Was it a white man?
>> No, it was not a white man. cuz that
would have been hilarious to go that
film with a white man and you're there
like really
with a black man and thankfully he
agreed with me cuz I was like I'm about
to have to leave this and figure out a
way to talk about this movie in a way
that doesn't insult him
>> because this was his choice and I can't
be such a negative Nancy
>> things like that. Look at all that math
you had to do.
>> I think the movie was trash.
>> And then he was like, "Okay, what did
you think of it?" And I was like, "How
about you go first? [laughter]
And thankfully we were on the same page,
but it was it was stressful FOR A SECOND
THERE.
>> There's my ramen. You guys, this has
been a delight. [laughter]
>> It really has been. Thank you so much
for being so generous with your time,
Amanda. Reminder that this is where you
can see Amanda on the book tour and the
book comes out on November 8th.
>> Yes. And you can watch the live stream
and get your tickets at amassals.com
to support. And remember, the Zios are
out here trying to shut me up and shut
us down. So, let's let's show up with
numbers. Even if you don't buy a book,
just come through and be like, AH, FROM
THE RIVER TO THE SEA. [laughter]
And uh it was great meeting you, Nathan.
And you all stay lifted. Don't give up
on astrology. [laughter]
>> There's a place There's a place for all
of us. All right. So, I will see you all
in the world. Bye, comrades. Bye,
comrades. Keep the faith.
>> All right, Nathan.
>> Hey, Rick.
>> I want to give you an opportunity to
really dig into what you think is going
on here. I I I will say to the audience,
I apologize. Um I feel like I should be
talking more about Zoron. I've been
checking to see if there's
>> Oh, yeah.
[laughter]
>> Slay on his cats for the last hour.
Well, let me let me ask you about this.
>> Great brain. That's what you are.
>> It's true. It's true. I can't be help.
I'm a little bit like Don't you a little
bit want to be a part of whatever this
movement is? Like just for the vibes?
>> No, I do. It's kind of crazy because the
the Guardian Agents is fake, right? Like
there aren't actually more than like 40
of [laughter] them in the whole city.
Isn't it like a fake a fake movement?
>> I don't I don't really know much about
the Guardian Angels. I was like
>> New York. Did you ever see one?
>> Never once. Never once. [laughter]
>> This is how important swag is though.
Look at this.
>> No, let me try to find some of the good
Siwa um uh shot I was the debate clips
where he really shows his character to
the world in a way that made him sort of
a lovable
a lovable character. There was a clip
about
the parades.
And there was a clip about getting shot.
>> All parades have a right to exist.
>> And I would choose either of them.
>> Parades have. [laughter] That's another
thing people kept asking me at this
party. What is your stance on parades?
Which I was very happy to pontificate
about. Okay, here we go.
>> Here we go. Oh, wait. This isn't this
isn't the one, but this is this is a
good one.
>> If there was a rank choice election, how
would you vote? Mr. from Donnie.
>> If there was a rank choice election
>> in this, you'd have to rank these
>> myself number one and Curtis number two.
>> Mr. SWA.
>> Oh, please don't be glazing me here.
Sora,
>> are you kidding?
>> Mr. Le, do I
>> I support rank choice voting, but I'd
only vote for myself.
>> Don't be glazing ME, ZORON.
[laughter]
THAT'S my guy. Like, come on. [crying]
Come on.
>> He's a magnificent character.
>> Look at this.
>> I know. There's something very likable
about I mean the problem is that he's
kind of a fascist thug. Like I mean the
details. I
>> if he like if he actually had a chance
of winning um he would be quite
frightening in a Trumpian way, right? I
mean, it's only because he stands no
chance of getting near power that we can
kind of enjoy uh these aspects of him.
[snorts]
>> Yeah. Yeah. Of course. Of course. But
Nathan, that being said, that being
said, wait, where's the parades one? Why
isn't Why isn't internet doing it?
>> Trump is kind of fun in this in this
same way. And Trump only becomes less
fun because he's got power.
Trump is the single most hilarious
politician that the world has ever seen,
>> right?
>> And as the light fades from our
collective eyes as humanity, we are
going to be laughing as we as the as the
nuclear bomb descends on our town or
whatever whatever ends up happening. I'm
confident that we will go out laughing.
>> Yeah.
>> That man
>> is as funny as he is evil. Did you see
this one? By the way, speaking of Trump
and Zuron and being low-key hilarious,
>> with state and local elections coming up
Tuesday, we asked the president about
the highly anticipated mayoral race that
includes former New York Governor Andrew
Cuomo and Zoron Mdani. Zorhan Mandami,
34year-old Democratic socialist. He's
the
>> communist, not socialist, communist.
He's far he's far worse than a
socialist. Some people have compared him
to a left-wing version of you.
Charismatic, breaking the old rules.
What do you think about that?
>> Well, I think I'm a much better looking
person than him, right?
>> With state and local election.
[laughter]
>> Like he's so vain. He's so absurd.
And for his his priorities in that were
to make sure that we understood that he
was a communist, not a socialist because
Trump identifies accurately that
socialism is popular now. But also
point, isn't it, isn't it interesting
that he had to say like he's not a
socialist like because he realized that
like the old uh tactic of calling people
socialists doesn't work. So now you got
to go like, "Oh, they're not a they're
not a socialist. They're a communist."
because that that still has some sting
to it.
>> 100%.
>> So,
>> Nathan, as as I continue to look for um
absurd clips to amuse myself, I really
did bring you here to get into this
bigger issue of what's next for the
left. So, on one hand, we're fighting
this battle over [snorts]
the uh centrists who are trying to
maintain their dominance.
>> Yeah. On the other hand, there is this
question that Amanda raised, re how do
we keep Zoron Mamani accountable in a
world where everyone is very excited to
win and is winning important no matter
what or is there a cost which we
shouldn't be willing to pay
>> and at what point do we start to cross
that line? Yeah, I I mean so right right
now as I was just checking again I think
we still we still don't know the uh the
election results but um in New York and
I was just in New York for a week and
one of the interesting things is people
are less worried about whether Zora will
win than what's going to happen if he
does win because if he does win uh it's
the probably the most important single
victory for an American democratic
socialist in history of the United
States of America. Um, I mean, I I know
New York had a mayor before who was a
member of the DSA, but I mean, it's a
huge it's like a I mean, it is a
takeover of the most important city in
the country um by the the DSA. And then
the question is uh what happens then? He
just um you know when all of these
forces come to bear against him that are
pressuring him to um moder you know
don't do public grocery stores, don't do
anything about the police. Um oh we
can't actually have free buses. Maybe
you could reduce the fair by 50%. Um
what's he going to do? and what he does
is [gasps]
going to determine what the in many ways
the future of the American left because
if he's [snorts]
in this in this the highest profile
American left is now in a position of
power. It's not like being in Congress
where you have this this ready-made
excuse which is, "Oh, I'm only one of
435 representatives. I can't do
anything." Right? He's a he's a chief
executive. Um there's going to be
expectations and if he sells out um that
that he's going to totally demoralize
the left, but I mean I think we all
recognize that you're going to have to
make certain compromises
um because you're not all powerful. So
the the the question is what as you say
what what is the line? So for example,
you know, in this campaign, he very
prominently backed down on his previous
criticisms of the NYPD. He used to say
they were racist, he not only no longer
says they're racist, he literally went
on Fox News to apologize directly to the
NYPD for having called them racist.
Well, the NYPD are still racist. So is
it going to be a lot more of that? Um,
is it going to are those just a few
things that he said thinking that he had
to do them in the election? I mean,
there's a huge amount of uncertainty now
that's going to depend on who it turns
out this guy actually is.
>> Let's also talk about this clip in which
he was asked by the Hellgate podcast.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Criticizing from the left about keeping
NYPD Commissioner Jessica Tish on board.
Let's
>> billionaires. Let's talk about Jessica
Tish. That was the big news this week.
[laughter]
I mean, lots of people who support your
candidacy care about criminal justice
reform and reforming the NYPD. And for
the past year, she has stood to thwart
that in many different ways. Um, she
wants to keep the gang database. She's
pushing a crackdown on low-level
offenses. She's ordering the NYPD to
issue criminal summones to deliveras.
I could go on.
>> She's the she was the face of uh the
effort to roll back discovery reform and
bail reform and now she wants to do like
mess with raise the age.
>> How do you square all of that with your
choice to make her your next police
commissioner?
>> [applause]
>> I think there is quite a bit that
applies in this answer not only to
Commissioner Tish but also to anyone
working underneath the Adams
administration
and that is the question of what is the
directive of the mayor and I am and I
have made this decision as a decision to
further my very public agenda of
delivering safety and justice and so
that's that means
This is a decision to build on what she
has done in entering Eric Adams's
NYPD that where he stacked the upper
echelons with corruption and
incompetence. She started to root that
out and also reduce crime and also to
create the Department of Community
Safety and also to disband the strategic
response group and also to actually
follow through on the exact agenda that
we've been running on. And I'm someone
who cares deeply about criminal legal
reform in Albany. have been on the front
lines of many of the fights to retain
much of the progress that was made and I
am going to be a mayor who will act in
the same manner.
>> So she's going to reverse her position
on all those things or she's going to do
she's going to follow your lead in city
hall if she's your police commissioner.
>> I think everyone will follow my lead.
I'll be the I'll be the mayor.
[laughter]
>> Well, uh we we'll see, won't we? I mean,
I
I I don't I mean, it's hard it's it's
hard to assess. I mean, he's he's laying
out a theory there which essentially
says, "Look, trust me, I believe in
these. I'm still progressive on on
criminal punishment reform. I still
believe in all of the things that I I
don't now, personally, I don't know that
much about policing in New York City
specifically. So, I don't really know
about her positions on on he he was
laying out some good things he said she
she'd done. I don't really know very
much about that. Um, but the theory here
is well, the police commissioner
responds to reports to the mayor. I'm
going to direct her to keep the good
things she's done and reverse the bad
things. Um, and then we'll see if he
does that. If he, you know, uh, he says,
I mean, I kind of like him saying like,
I'm the mayor, people are going to do
what I say. Um, but
>> [laughter]
>> Do you or because it strikes me as
deeply naive and a and as a dodge to be
honest. Can you imagine a world in which
Eric Adams keep some you know Chessa
Bodden style
uh leftists on board his team.
>> Let me ask hard to imagine that actually
happening.
>> And let me ask it this other way. With
Zoron being up as he has been in the
polls and having so conclusively won the
primary, what why what's the rationale
for keeping Jessica Tish on board who
additionally is a Zionist who was very
supportive of the police crackdown on
pro Palestinian students? The very
students who got Zoron elected knocking
on doors of 50,000 strong, etc., etc.
>> Yeah. I mean, on the surface, if you're
going to do it, if you are going to be a
a dictator of a mayor and bring these
people in line, um then that could work.
But the way we've seen it before is um
you know Obama keeping like uh Bush's uh
uh CIA director on or you know it
doesn't in in in general you when you
bring people who totally disagree with
your agenda on uh what actually happens
is they undermine you at every stage and
they make it so that it's impossible to
carry out the things that you believe
in. So while if he does sit down on day
one and say, "Look, everyone who is in
this administration has to carry out my
agenda or you can leave." Um if he if he
does that and follows through on that,
then in theory that's going to produce
good reforms. Um but as you say, it's
it's kind of hard to imagine it actually
happening.
If I invited a,
sorry to be maximalist with this
analogy, but if I invited a robewearing
clans member to a dinner party
and other people in the room objected
and I said, "Look, look, look, I
understand that this is a robeswearing
clan member, but I'm not going to kick
him out until he actually says something
racist."
That would feel a little silly. It would
feel almost like I was looking for space
to allow to justify the presence of this
person whose ideology is very clear,
whose commitments are very clear,
saying, "Well, they're in my house, so
they're going to follow my rules." The
question is, why do I want them there?
>> Even if they do follow my rules in a
superficial sort of way, and not try to
hang any of my dinner guests or call
them the n-word,
>> right?
>> Yeah. I mean, well, that's why I say,
you know, he's citing a series of of
supposedly positive things that she did
there. And I I don't really know about
those uh enough about those things to
know if there is like an affirmative
case for this person's presence.
>> I I mean, there isn't there isn't an
affirmative case for it. But look here,
let me go back to your earlier point
that you made, Nathan, about what it
means for the left given how much
attention there is on Zuron if his
agenda is ultimately thwarted. Because,
you know, to the the bigger point here,
he's the mayor of a city. The purse
strings are held in Albany. Kathy Hokll
was late to endorse. My theory is that
she ultimately did endorse the
Democratic nominee in those words
because she is being challenged by her
former lieutenant governor um Anthony
Delgado who I interviewed and you can
hear him on Bad Faith podcast. Anthony
Delgado is positioning himself as more
of a Zoron friendly candidate
and and you know she if if not being if
not for the fact that she was being
primar I don't know that we would have
gotten what we got out of her. Notably,
when she attended Zoron's rally, what
was it last week or the week before? She
praised the crowd for turning out in big
numbers and praised Zoron for
galvanizing the youth without talking
about any of his substantive pol
policies and has previously said that
she did not endorse his policy to tax
the rich and would not be allowing
funding for some of his other efforts.
Here's her basically saying some of that
in a recent interview from a day or two.
>> We know that mom Donnie does want to tax
the rich more, bring it up about 2%. He
can't do that on his own. You've
previously said that you wouldn't be
raising taxes. Have you reconsidered
that stance?
>> No. I will say uh one energetic rally
does not get me to change my positions,
I assure you. Um but I do hear people's
voices. I process what everybody says,
but I'm also have to balance uh
governing this state and making sure
that those people who are actually the
reason we have a generous supportive
budget that helps lift people up, it's
their revenues that we tax. One and a
half% of New Yorkers cover about a third
of our budget. That's enormous. I'm
concerned about out migration of people
who are the ones who are supporting our
budget. I cannot make up for that with
middle class tax increases. I cannot do
that to the middle class and the
struggling New Yorkers. So, so this is
the balance. I mean, this is my
position.
All right. So, if Zuron is being set up
to fail,
is there more here? Here's how I would
put this. This is how I put it in a very
sort of I think productive but intense
debate that I had in the episode that is
coming out on Thursday with Osa Noevu.
If we all kind of understand that this
is largely symbolic because he's going
to be thwarted at every turn by the
NYPD, by his own democratically elected
governor and all those kinds of things,
is the value of winning what we should
be focused on versus the value of him
using his platform to change the shift
to Overton window on major left
priorities including Gaza the way he
does on has on Gaza. And if the
messaging is at least as important as
what he can accomplish in office given
the limits that are going to be put on
him in office, how do we feel about his
retrenchment on issues like criminal
justice and ultimately some retrenchment
on the issue of Palestine as well?
>> What you mean the uh the antifod thing?
>> The antifod thing, the change in
language. I won't call it full-blown
backtracking, but the change in language
about uh arresting Netanyahu
and the caucusing with self-described
liberal Zionists that also got some push
back.
>> It's not actually clear. I mean, I I
don't I wouldn't take it as given that
he is definitely going to be thwarted at
every turn, right? Because I mean, she
she said that there in that clip, "Oh, I
you know, I'm not going to change my
position because of one rally." Well,
no, that's right. But you're going to
change your position when you sense a
political threat. So if you're able to
build I mean that's as you as you
mentioned that's why she endorsed him in
the first place after not endorsing him.
She endorsed him. A lot of these
politicians are completely unprincipled
and only looking out for their own
interests. So if the calculus of their
interest, right? So Zoran has an
overwhelming victory. There's a massive
movement. There's clearly a ground swell
of demand for free child care in New
York City put with a with a tax
increase. all of a sudden, you know, I I
I do think there's a danger of accepting
the narrative that, oh well, uh, the the
Democrats in Albany are never going to
let this [laughter] happen. And they
want you to believe that, right? They
they they say this in the Atlantic. Oh,
Zoron can't do anything because Kathy
Hok's never going to let it happen.
Well, uh, she would like us to believe
that. They would like us to believe
that. Um, but if there's massive popular
support and there's a credible political
threat against them, all of a sudden
they're going to start pretending it was
their idea all along. Um, and they're
all going to start shifting towards the
Zoron agenda. So if he can get a few big
things through because he builds a
popular movement in favor of these
things and if they're really good and
positive and make a huge difference for
the people of New York, um I think
that's actually going to be important um
because it's going to show that you can
actually accomplish one or two things
that really change people's lives. Um
it's going to show that you can
successfully put pressure on the party
establishment. Um, and if he just
governs as a really really good mayor
who manages to change a few important
things, um, I think that's a positive
uh, for the left.
>> I believe that people can be moved and
he could achieve something like free
busing.
I believe he can be allowed to open five
grocery stores, publicly owned grocery
stores.
I am very skeptical that he can be moved
on anything that implicates the
billionaire donor class in New York, the
city with more billionaires than
anywhere else in the world. And so what
does it mean about socialism to have
socialism branded as limited sort of
free buses? I I don't denigrate that
policy in the least, of course, but that
that's sort of the totality of the
achievement. If to achieve free buses,
you have to be willing to sit down at
the table with a business interest in
New York and have yourself described in
a New York Times article as not really
being a socialist, more being a
capitalist, being open to those all the
things that as Steve Herdon wrote about
in that piece.
>> And what does it mean? You know, if
ultimately you are collapsing the
differences, you're collapsing the gulf
between the people and capital instead
of elucidating it and explaining to the
people the way that he explained to the
public and move the public on the issue
of Israel's right to exist as as an
aparttheid state. At what point does he
reify
the capitalist system that he is now in
charge of in New York City? I mean, in
many ways, the same questions would have
faced us if Bernie Sanders had become
president and we had a big push for the
I mean, the equivalent of free buses
might have been, you know, Medicare for
all, right? Where it's not a fully
nationalized health care system. It's
literally a very incremental thing,
which is
>> I just I just I have to disagree on that
one. I think there's a big gulf between
universal health care, the implications
of universal health care for people's
being ability to continue to leave their
jobs, mobilize for something more uh the
freedom that it comes to to unions for
not only have to fight around healthcare
but being free to fight around other
kinds of issues etc. Then
>> compare it to the child care the free
child care. Uh, I mean, I I I'm not
saying that they're on the same. I'm
saying that the same questions would
face us, right? If if Bernie Sanders had
become president, his signature policy
is to expand an existing social program,
Medicare, um, to cover everyone. And
it's not a radical program. It doesn't
really I mean, it eliminates most of the
private insurance industry, but it
doesn't create a nationalized health
care system on the on the lines of the
UK National Health Service. I mean, it
as these things go, it's just bringing
the United States in line with European
social democracies, right? It's Yeah,
it's a it makes a huge difference in
working people's lives, but it is not
that, as he emphasizes over and over,
it's not that radical of a of a program.
Um, but you'd have the you'd have the
same kinds of things where you're like,
is Bernie, you know, really a a
capitalist who's who's just, you know,
supporting this incremental reform?
Ultimately, I think it would have been
to the good to have a Bernie Sanders
presidency if it brought about Medicare
for all and and nothing else. Just as I
think it'd be good to have a Zoron mer
if it moves the conversation on Israel
Palestine in a really important way. If
he gets free child care for all of the
people of New York, that's pretty
positive. Um,
>> and if it moves the conversation about
billionaires taxing the rich, the the
fact that our emiseration is because of
the aggregation of wealth, the 1%. If it
moves that conversation to the right,
>> if it moves that conversation to the
right because suddenly the conversation
goes away because Ramadan is obliged to
protect the interest of the billionaire
class so that Kathy Hokll can keep
taxing them. Then what does that do?
>> Well, then that would be bad, right? So,
we're going to have to see where it
goes. But I think that I I I I tend to
think that Azoron victory is going to
make it more uh politically with
possible to talk about tax increases on
the rich. Um that it's going to increase
the amount of pressure on people like
Kavie Hogal to buckle on this because
they're going to see that there's a
ground swell of popular support for it.
Um but we're again we're going to see
we're really in uncharted territory
here. So um
>> I think we're in charted territory. I
think we're in charted territory. I
think we're in the territory where we've
never seen a progressive candidate move
to more to the left after they've gotten
elected. I think that's very charted
territory because not because of their
like spirit or their heart or anything
like that, because of the nature of the
pressures that they're under.
>> Yeah. Well,
>> yeah. Go ahead. Go ahead. Sorry. I don't
think he's going to move more to the
left, but I mean there's a question as
to what
to what degree is he going to hold the
line. Um, and I don't know.
>> I'm trying to pull up in my big stack of
papers if I can find. Yeah, here it is.
The article that I've already marked up
so I don't have to print it out again.
>> Um, I want to just revisit this. I know
I talked about this in a recent episode,
but I want to make sure that people
understand that this isn't me coming
from like a place of negativity or
wanting to find things wrong with Zoron.
It's for me feeling like I have an
obligation to talk about what's already
in the public record. For weeks and
months, people have been saying, "Well,
wait till he wins and then we can hold
him to account." I think that was silly
for the reasons I talked about earlier
with Amanda. But even if you adopt that
approach, I keep checking. I don't see
an official
he's one thing yet.
Um, I do see that the Virginia candidate
won that, um, Spanberger won and beat
Errol Sears. That's less of a concern
for us as leftists, but I guess it's
good for Democrats. Let me read this
excerpt, and you tell me what you think.
For months now, Mumani has been meeting
privately with former leaders in the
city government, business executives,
head of New York arts and cultural
institution, and skeptical local
Democrats. The talks are pitched as get
to know you discussions with the new
political star, but they also serve a
dual purpose. According to people with
knowledge of the conversations in them,
Mumdani has sought to present himself as
a new type of leftist. A listener who
understands his shortcomings and is
willing to grow. He has acknowledged his
lack of managerial experience and asked
for advice. He has sought common ground.
He has heard out his critics, including
wealthy New Yorkers and in business and
finance and some pro-Israel activists
who are turned off by his lifelong
advocacy for Palestinians or offended by
his reluctance to immediately condemn
the phrase globalize the inifat.
There have been two critical liaison.
Patrick Gasbart, a former Obama
administration aid and director of the
Democratic National Convent uh committee
and Sally Susman, a longtime corporate
executive and member of the finance
committees for the presidential
campaigns of Barack Obama, Hillary
Clinton and Joe Biden. Gasbard met
Mandani years ago. Susman met him this
summer. one of several seeds who
privately reached out to him after his
much talked about July meeting with the
partnership for New York City consortium
of 350 members representing banks, law
firms, and corporations. Susman, who
describes herself as a moderate pro
business Democrat, said that she was
impressed by how Mumani handled himself
amid a hostile crowd. Weeks later, she
met with him for an hour at her request
and said she left that interaction taken
by his curiosity. She recalled that he
asked questions like, "What do you know
about game-changing leadership and how
should I form an administration?" And
made clear that there would be no litmus
tests for staff roles in his cabinet.
Susman has since become a valuable ally,
convening two intimate gatherings at
Mumdan's campaign office. This time at
his request for business leaders and
tech investors eager to meet him. Quote,
"There's something about him that makes
people want to help him," she told me.
Robert Wolf, another partnership for New
York City member and a major fundraiser
for the Democratic party, told me that
he has begun texting with the candidate,
becoming an informal pulse check for the
city's finance and business community.
Wol also met with Mandani for an hour at
his campaign office this month, an
in-person follow-up to an hourlong Zoom
meeting in August. Quote, Zuron to me is
more of a progressive capitalist, Wolf
told me, adding that he was convinced by
their private interactions that Mandani
understood the importance of the private
sector thriving in New York. quote,
"He's someone that wants to figure out
how to use the government in an
appropriate way on things that help
equality and the underserve and help the
underserved."
The conversations have allowed Mumani to
reframe his previous positions, tweaking
the us versus them language of his
democratic socialist values to be a tad
less punitive. He has made it clear that
he wants to support renters, not punish
landlords. He wants to support public
education, not take a hammer to
specialized schools with elite
admissions. He supports Palestinian
rights. He is not anti-Zionist.
He made key concessions when it came to
policing. Importantly, he made clear
that he was open to compromise when it
came to his proposed millionaires tax.
Call it Mumani 2.0.
>> Is that the New York the New York Times?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Uh I did point out uh on Twitter
this anti not anti-sionist thing and and
the response I got from some people was
that that was the New York Times's
characterization
>> but that
>> they it wasn't clear what they based
that on because I don't think that he
has actually
a lot of Mandali supporters were
disputing that he had said anything that
would legitimately be characterized as
not anti-s uh anti-ionist.
I think that's very fair. And when I
covered this the first time on Bad
Faith, I said exactly that that a lot of
it was characterization of a steed
>> whose politics during 2020 I recall as
being very much not in the Bernie camp.
>> So that's neither here nor there.
They might not think he's anti-ionist,
but uh he I mean he's affirmed pretty
consistently he doesn't believe that
Israel should exist as a Jewish state,
which uh
I mean the way he the phrase he uses is
he doesn't believe in that any state
should have a hierarchy of ethnicity,
which essentially translates to Israel
should not be able to exist as a Jewish
state in particular. Um which is pretty
clearly anti-ionist. I mean, it's kind
of definitionally anti- Zionist. Um,
anyway, uh, so whether he's backed off
on that, I I I don't think we have
evidence that he has. I think mainly
people his his kind of phrasing is is
working successfully to convince people
he's not hostile to Israel, even though
the implications of what he's saying are
quite uh are quite hostile to Israel's
basic structure. Um,
again, like is he playing these people?
I don't know.
>> [laughter]
>> like um you know is he I mean is he
saying like I'll sit down and hear you
out and then I'm going to go do what I'm
going to do um and it you know the I'm
going to if it if it help if it appeases
them or throws them off guard for me to
have a meeting where I just nod and
smile then it's worth doing um in and
picking his battles. I don't know.
Again, we're going to there these things
are concerning. Um we're going to have
to see what he actually does. Uh
presuming he wins and currently he's
winning. Yes.
>> Uh so apparently he reportedly is at
51%. He has won. I'm looking for an
actual confirmation of the victory. I
see people in the chat saying he's won.
Here's a screen grab from CNN with Zoron
at 51.5% Cuomo
at 39.7.
Sua boop boop at 8%.
>> There's your man
>> and%
the way we all forgot he is currently
the mayor of New
>> Eric Adams. That guy. Who's that?
>> Mark.
>> Oh yeah, there we go.
>> is wild. See what
the chat is saying. NBC
He called it for Zoron already.
Um, shout out to you.
Um, a characterization glitching. Am I
Can you guys hear me,
>> Nathan?
>> I'm I'm losing.
>> My bad. I think sometimes when I share
my screen, my computer like can't handle
it. So I'll try to keep that to a
minute.
>> Um I do see I do see having yeah
projected winner Zoron Modani. So
>> okay
>> so we're gonna find out what he does.
>> We're gonna find out. So taking
everything you said about um the New
York Times piece characterizing him. We
don't know what he actually thinks. I
will leave you with this quote. The
quote is
um this is from Mumani. Being right in
and of itself is meaningless. Mani told
me when I asked about his approach to
these meetings, quote, "We have to win
and we have to deliver."
>> Yeah.
>> Take from that what you will. Being
right in and of itself is meaningless. I
would like to hear some follow-up
questions about what one should be
willing to give up to concede either in
real life or rhetorically behind the
scenes in order to win. And the point
that Shama has been making throughout
this race is that
you have to you should make sure that
you are not doing the work
of collapsing the fa the differences
between your project and the
main the Democratic establishment's
project and that you are
clarifying
what's motivating the Democrats and
being honest about the limits of their
reforms because of who they are and what
their goals are. Oh, speak of the devil.
>> Speak of the devil. Nathan, I want to
make sure that you know that you were
not this is not a hostage situation.
>> Time you've been very generous with your
time. I called you in the last
>> at any point.
>> Yeah, sure. I I love Sha. Can I just
make one one more point from the the
centism article. So in in that idea that
he that Mdani voiced there which is okay
it's not enough to be right you also
have to win. I kind of agree with that
but as you point out one of the
arguments the New York Times was making
in that centism piece was they the whole
piece was framed around uh centrist
politics can win. They are they are they
are what it and and the whole thing was
like that oh if you abandon trans people
if you abandon uh you know concern about
racism you know it could bump you up one
or two points and one of the core points
that I did make in the article was okay
but what you know you lose your you you
totally lose sight of what you're
actually fighting for. You know, if we
proved that the civil rights movement
was unpopular in 1963, I wouldn't prove
that you should jettison civil rights in
order to get elected because that's the
what the whole fight is about. So it is
true that you know if you start thinking
in these terms of of what do I have to
do in order to to win and you stop
thinking entirely in terms of ideology
and the moral stakes of of politics. Um
you you may win and then you'll have but
at what cost you you'll have forgotten
what the entire fight is about. Um so I
do think I accept that caution about uh
about Mdani and it does it does concern
me deeply but anyway that's all I'll
say. No, I really liked that part of
your your article as well, Nathan. And I
want to extend a warm welcome to Shama
Swant who has been I would argue one of
the most no probably the most
ideologically consistent touchston for
us as we have navigated this election
which is ultimately a candidate running
as a Democrat in New York City who is
really kind of testing the limits of
what the left can achieve within a uh
Democratic party context. Welcome back
to Bad Faith.
>> Thanks so much for having me and hi
Nathan.
>> Hi.
>> So I'm sure you caught uh some of what
we were talking about. I was reading
some quotes from the Assadhuran piece
about Zaramani that came out a couple of
weeks ago in which uh he is
characterized as being willing to meet
with the business community soliciting
their advice describing himself as an
anti-ionist. Although to be clear that's
how he's characterized in the article,
it's not clear that that is what he
actually said himself. Um, and it of
course reminded me and I see other
people in the chat and people in my
audience over on Patreon of some of the
things that you warned about many months
ago around the time he won the primary.
So, what's your takeaway from his
victory tonight?
My main takeaway is that the
working-class demands that he ran on
were incredibly popular. And he did run
a Bernie style campaign in the sense
that he focused relentlessly on those
demands. I mean, admittedly, he did not
actually talk about the $30 an hour
minimum wage for New York, which I think
is officially on his program, but he
didn't really emphasize it for the most
part. However, those are the demands
that are really popular for the working
class. And it came, this campaign came
at a moment when the working class is so
angry. I mean, you've talked about this,
Briana, on your shows and also in your
interview with Mark Lamont Hill that the
working class is so angry. I mean, look
at this poll that came out recently, the
New York ABC News Washington Post poll
that shows that more than 60% of the
American working class thinks Trump,
Republicans, and Democrats all are out
of touch. All both parties and Trump,
they're all out of touch. But they think
that the Democratic party is more out of
touch than even the Republicans or than
even Trump. So it is at that mo this
moment of working-class people feeling
such betrayal by both parties that any
candidate running on actual demands, you
know, on making buses free, making
grocery stores much more accessible
through public organizing. All of this
is extremely popular. And I think the
main point is something that you and
Nathan were chatting about a few minutes
ago, which is that the the test is what
does he actually do with this position?
Because in order to win any of those
demands, you know, it's obviously I
agree with you, Briana, that winning a
$30 an hour minimum wage is going to be
far harder than maybe winning some bus
routes free or something like that.
Although even that will be hard. So the
point is that it everything will need a
fight back. And just one other thing
I'll say before I stop is that at this
moment I mean the the Mandani election I
mean this is this has captured the
imagination
of tens of millions of American working
people. It has become an international
phenomenon. So anything that the working
class can win through Mamani's election
will be seen as an enormous
working-class victory. So I think we
should expect that the capitalist class,
the ruling class are going to be
extremely determined not to let any of
those demands win because of the
symbolism. You know what it means that
you that you could actually have this
type of volunteer-run people powered
campaign and actually win. And bottom
line is you can't win without a fight
back. I mean all the victories that we
won in Seattle through my one elected
socialist revolutionary socialist office
that all came because I absolutely went
there as a disruptor of business as
usual. I was not having meetings with
the billionaires.
>> Yeah. I mean so I'm I have this Zuron
just posted this uh victory post
literally minutes ago. It's the subway
pulling up but the doors opening at city
hall. Obviously there's an enormous
amount of excitement. there's 10,000
likes on this thing that just went up
literally three minutes ago. Um,
and so it does feel like he has this
very
large popular front behind him. the fact
that he was able to win with so many
tens and thousands of uh volunteers. The
fact that he, you know, exponentially
increased turnout, including among young
voters, in a way that Bernie Sanders was
ultimately not able to do, even though
his sort of victory was premised on
being able to do so. He does have a
mandate of sorts. And there could be a
world where we see something happen that
we've never seen before, which is that
someone wins, feels safe in having
secured their victory, and then goes
ham, goes balls to the wall, starts
saying all the things that they maybe
didn't feel safe to say in the primary.
And maybe now we suddenly get this
conversation where he's willing to say,
"F Jessica Tish. Actually, she's out.
She's a cop. Cops are racist. Actually,
also, I'm 100% gonna arrest Netanyahu.
y'all can't do anything about it for the
next four years. So, you better sit
tight because it's my house now. Sure,
that could happen. It's never happened.
It could happen. But I want to ask you
what you make of the clip. I don't know
if you were here for this, but there was
a clip we played of Kathy Hokll saying
that she did not support his uh taxing
the billionaire's agenda because she
feared them fleeing the city. in
combination with this quote from the New
York Times piece uh in which the
business interest said he was willing to
sit down with them and that he was quote
more of a progressive capitalist uh than
a socialist. You've spoken to me in the
past about, as you just mentioned, not
willing to sit down with those business
leaders, needing to make it clear to the
public that those were the people that
were thwarting the broad populist eo
economic populist goals that they were
looking to achieve and that these things
were zero sum and mutually exclusive.
So, what do you have to say about the
posture that Mamani's been taking?
First of all, I think you know the the
hypothetical and I'll call it a
hypothetical that you posed about you
know somebody who has been making some
concessions during his election but then
once they feel safe and secured as you
said once they win the election then
they'll go ball to the wall.
There's no example [laughter] of that.
So if we were going to be I mean if this
was a statistics class and I used to
teach statistics in college. If this was
a statistics class and any of my
students said, you know, that could
happen, I would say, well, you know,
you're just not looking at the
statistical evidence. And in this case,
the evidence is actually zero. Like
there is no case that we know of where
after taking office, the elected
representative moved more to the left
out of their own choice. I mean you can
see lots of things happening in his you
know historically through the pressures
of mass movements and pressures you know
FDR passing the new deal that was done
under pressure from mass movements and
specifically revolutionary movements
including the teamster general strike in
Minneapolis. So that that type of
phenomenon can push and will push the
capitalist process.
However, this idea that somebody uh was
not feeling in safe enough during the
election, but then they moved left once
they elected, that doesn't that's never
happened. And I'll tell you why. It's
not only that I'm relying on statistical
evidence to have this position, but
scientifically does not make sense. Why?
Because when you're running, if you're
running on working-class demands, you
come under intense pressure. even when
you're running and I'm, you know, I'm
speaking from personal experience from
the from my first election campaign for
city council in 2013 and so on. We had
tremendous, you know, we had all these
Democratic party operatives and now
people who have since been elected to
office actually coming to me and saying,
"Well, don't call yourself socialist. Do
you have to start every speech by saying
you're a socialist? Do you always have
to talk about the $15 minimum wage? Can
you tone it down? can you, you know,
list as a member of the Democratic
party? Why are you running as an
independent? On and on and on. And I
didn't bend on any single one of those.
Because what happens is that if you bend
on any of those things, what you do is
you're sending a signal to the ruling
class, to the Democratic Party, that you
are malleable by them. And that means
only one thing. It means that they sense
blood in the water and they go for the
kill. They want more and more and more
because no amount of there's no there's
no um finite limit to how much appeasing
you can do of the ruling class. You
know, it's not like you can say, "Oh, uh
I'll meet with the billionaires and I
will retain the billionaire police
commissioner, but I am going to fight
against racism in NYPD. I am going to
push for workingclass needs because in
order to push for and win anything, you
are going to need to fight against the
very people you are trying to appease,
you know. So there's no it's like trying
to square a circle and it it doesn't
matter when you try to square the
circle. The circle will always be a
circle and if you're trying to square
it, you're not going to it's not going
to work. So it doesn't matter when and
it's furthermore once you get elected
the pressures on you compound
exponentially.
So I think that the most benign thing I
can say about this is that somebody
would be naive to think that that is
going to work. Uh you know if they if
they think that they can get elected and
then they can do it. I mean if I don't
know what I'm not a mind reader. I'm not
saying that he's thinking these things.
I'm saying that if indeed that is the
contention anybody is making then the
best thing I can I have to say about
that is that that is naive but honestly
I don't even think that's what's
happening I think what's happening is
the same old story there's nothing new
here in the sense that uh we have seen
so many democratic socialists of America
elected representatives or you know
endorsed by the democratic socialists of
America elected representatives there
are hundreds of them throughout the
nation there are four on the New York
City council
And what have we seen them do? Virtually
nothing. I mean, nothing. I mean, maybe
maybe they did marginal things, but
nothing absolutely nothing unfortunately
for the working class. Absolututely
nothing comparable to what we did in
Seattle. And and the reason is that if
you are trying to sort of make some
peace with the ruling class and yet do
something for the working class, you end
up actually not serving the working
class at all. And you end up generally
appeasing the ruling class more and more
and more because for the simple reason
that you can't serve both working people
and the ruling class. You have to choose
a side because the interests of the
working class and the greed and the
profits of the ruling class are these
are diametrically opposed. You know we
didn't make the system. The system is
what it is and it is our job to
understand that. It's been so difficult
for me as I've been trying to explain
this point, especially knowing that, you
know, I can be easily characterized as a
hater,
for lack of a better word. I I heard
you, you know, mention the interview I
did recently with um Mark Lamont Hill. I
appreciated the opportunity to make the
pitch there in some way and but I've
been thinking about you know how to say
that concisely like how do you make
people understand that it's not about
this isn't an assessment of Mumani or
any other leftists
will or desire or personal integrity
belief in self capacity as a politician
natural skill anything like that but
that it's akin into
thinking that you're going to convince
your jailer to let you free when their
entire livelihood depends on them
keeping that job when you know their
mortgage needs to be paid by the only
job they can get which is to be your
jailer. I mean, it's, you know,
politics is like a dam and, you know,
there's water on one side and it's dry
and safe on the other side. And there's
this argument that like we can convince,
you know, the dam wants to break and we
can convince it somehow to only like
crack and then we're all going to be
safe. Like these are this is like a
zero- sum situation when we're talking
about the economic institutions that
have designed the system the way that it
has. that that capitalism really is the
problem here.
I I don't know. It it feels it feels
like it's I get when when like kind of
normies don't really think in those
terms. It is a little bizarre to me and
frustrating when leftists will respond
to me and this is you know I have an
episode coming out tomorrow where people
will hear this argument like hashed out
in full or on on Thursday rather. hear
it hash out in full, but
the the like, well, we'll wait and see.
I guess we'll see what happens. It feels
like a little bit of a
I don't want to say a cope, but like no,
I don't have to wait and see because I
thought we were we were we understood
the structural realities of what we're
dealing with. I don't have to wait and
see if paper will catch fire if I put it
in a flame.
>> Yes. Exactly. I mean the starting point
is exactly what you said Brianna that
capitalism is a zero sum game. It's not
our imagination. It is so the fact is
that capitalism is a zero- sum game. And
so if you have political representatives
who are trying to make peace with or
trying to kind of serve the ruling class
then they are going to betray the
working class. And it doesn't it doesn't
have to be and it shouldn't be a
question of intentions. I mean
ultimately it does become a question of
intentions and integrity but you don't
doesn't have to be your starting point.
That doesn't need to be the debate. The
debate mainly needs to be about
strategy. Does that strategy of trying
to make pe keep make peace with the
ruling class. Does that work for the
working class? Absolutely not. What it
does work for is the careers of those
political representatives for the
careers of the labor bureaucrats you
know careers of all these middle layer
which I call gatekeepers. Yeah. It makes
for very convenient, well- paid,
lucrative careers. It makes for mainly,
it's not even just about money, by the
way, for this middle layer, for the
gatekeeper layer. It's about the fact
that if you defy the ruling class, even
marginal, even slightly, they will come
at you so hard that you need to you need
there's no way to not fight them. And so
people, these people, the elected
leaders, the DSA leaders, progressive
Democrats like AOC and Bernie Sanders,
all of them, they have made their own
personal calculations that they are not
going to take on that fight. Why?
Because it's [ __ ] hard. It is hard.
Not that I'm not saying that to justify
them or give them cover. My point is
that it is hard and but it that is what
needs to be done. So as far as Mandani
is concerned, I mean the re he has real
potential to do something similar to
what we did through my uh city council
office in Seattle. If only he would
actually do it. I mean now the news
reports are saying that over 100,000
ordinary people working and young people
volunteered for him. That is an army.
That's the army that can har be
harnessed to win any of the demands that
he has brought forward. The question is,
is he going to harness that army? And
I'll tell you something, you once you
start harnessing that army, once you
start putting that together to actually
win something for the working class,
that will upset the Democratic
leadership that he is trying to woo and
he's trying to be on good terms with. It
will absolutely alienate him from the
Democratic leadership. There are no two
ways about it. They're they they don't
they're not going to accept any middle
ground because there isn't any middle
ground. Either you win for the working
class or you don't. That's how it is.
And so if you actually do what I did,
which was use my office to build
movements to win the what what is now
the nation's highest minimum wage, the
Amazon tax on wealthy corporations to
fund affordable housing to the tune of
hundreds of millions of dollars every
year. If you win the unprecedented
renters rights we won, it will make you
enemy number one for the as far as the
ruling class and the dem Democratic
party is concerned. I mean you will have
a target on your back. That is how it
is. But the po the problem is the issue
is that there is no other way to achieve
what we have achieved. I mean there is
no other way to actually fight for and
win for the working class other than
having leaders who actually understand
that that is what it takes and that
there's no peaceful route to winning
reforms let alone ending capitalism and
ushering in socialism. So other in other
words, the question to Mandani is the
classic labor question. Which side are
you on? And if you're on the side of the
working class, then why on earth would
you be convening meetings with the
billionaires? And also, as soon as you
win, are you are you going to uh you
know, are you going to actually harness
put that army into into action? I mean,
I have already pledged. I mean, I'm
running for Congress against genocidal
billionaire backed Democrat Adam Smith.
I have already publicly pledged that if
I am elected, which we have a real shot
to get elected. If I am elected that I
will turn my congressional inauguration
in Washington DC into a mass rally of
10,000 people and I will immediately
start building the mass campaigns to win
an end to all US military aid to Israel
and uh free healthcare for all funded by
taxing the rich. this that we we don't
we don't see this type of language from
the Mandanis of the world and the simple
reason is that you know setting their
intentions aside and assuming even the
best of that what what what they do
understand is that is that if you make
those kinds of promises you will have to
live up to them but most importantly it
will immediately put you at odds with
the Democratic party leadership but you
know what the other side of the story
which we have to put in focus here is
that there's tens of millions of people
out there who are angry. They are angry
and they want a fight back. And yes,
there are lots of lots of hopes spinned
on Mamani. There is there's no question
about that. But it's also true that
people want results. People understand
that we've had many rounds of this
merrygoround. You know, we've we've done
this so many times. And you know, I I
just wanted to also say one one quick
thing. Briana, you've posed this as a
question. and you did this uh in the
Alazer interview and also tonight which
is that what is more important winning
as you said winning the election or
winning for the working class and also
setting the correct example for the
working class I think that's the correct
way of posing the question because uh it
if you make it about winning on at any
cost meaning winning at the cost of um
of um making concessions that actually
uh put put you at odds with what's
needed for the working class then it's
not worth it. However, uh we do want to
win. We have I won four elections. One
of them was a recall fight against me by
Trump related uh Republicans and the
Democratic party did absolutely nothing
to help me fight that recall. We still
defeated it. Why? Because the working
class was on my side. And the reason the
working class was on my side is because
I have never sold out. So it is possible
for us to win for the working class
including elections. And the reason I'm
running for Congress is the same reason
I ran for city council is not for my my
own career. And this is the crucial
difference. I'm not a careerist. So for
me I am dead serious about winning
elections. But why? So that I can use
that elevated platform to better you
know much organize stronger movements of
the working class to win offensive
victories. So if it's done on that
basis, we can win. But at the same time,
we're not going to win every fight. And
so the bottom line in every fight as
you're in and this is a this is you know
relating to your the way you posed the
question. The bottom line is you don't
send out a wrong message. So even if it
means you don't win that time, you have
to do the correct thing. And that is
what I was saying to Bernie Sanders
also. And obvious obviously that was
2014. Now he has thoroughly capitulated
to the to the democratic establishment.
He has you know Bernie Sanders has sold
out. AOC has has sold out and so uh yeah
we we need the correct examples and then
that part of that is running
independent. That is why you know a lot
of people even now will say why don't
you run as a Democrat? I mean seriously
people hate the Democratic party. Why
would I run as a Democrat now of all
times? And furthermore, it is about
sending the correct educational lessons
to the working class, which is that we
need a new party for the working class.
We're not going to run as Democrats. And
the way we won 15, the, you know, the,
for example, the 15 struggle here in
Seattle was we we launched 15 now using
my office. The Democrats hated it. There
was not a single Democrat ready to vote
yes at that time. We built neighborhood
action groups. We held mass organizing
conferences that were attended by
thousands of people. We held mass
rallies, mass protest marches. And then
most importantly in some ways, we
launched a ballot initiative campaign
which collected tens of thousands of
signatures which became a credible
threat to the Democratic party that if
they didn't vote yes on our $15 measure
on the city council, we were going to go
directly to the voters and it could win
and it had a real shot at winning. That
is how we won. And that is also how we
won the Amazon tax. We actually launched
a massive movement on the ground. We
held action conferences and we brought
in a ballot initiative campaign that
collected 30,000 signatures in three
months. And we were able to win the
Amazon tax even though the so-called
progressive Democrats were also against
us.
I want to just briefly go to Fox News
calling the victory for Zeron, but I
want to come back as Shama and ask you a
question about um what it is like to run
outside of the two-party system for
Congress.
>> Uh the Fox News decision desk can now
project
New York City has [music] elected
Democrat uh assemblyman Zoron Mdani to
be its next mayor. Now, he will become
the first Muslim mayor of the city and
its youngest in more than a century. Um,
not really a surprise. Um, I don't know
why people were waking up in the last,
you know, two and a half weeks. Uh, I
think they should have woke up after the
primary where he handily defeated Andrew
Cuomo.
>> Uh, [laughter]
>> okay. I can't help but be very amused by
the collective meltdown over this.
That being said, I recently interviewed
an independent candidate running against
Richie Torres uh for I think it's New
York's 15th district in the Bronx. Uh I
saw Andrew Andre Eastston tweet earlier
after Zuron's win was announced saying
the Bronx is ready for socialism. He's
obviously fired up. He also shared some
of your concerns and criticisms of what
the Zuron moment should mean versus what
it could mean versus what it likely
would mean when he was on the show just
last week. But one topic I didn't get
into with him was this sort of
structural realities of running as an
independent. Some people in my audience
had this as a follow-up question, which
is basically, I like him, he sounds
good, but can he really have a chance
running against um Richie Torres if he's
not running as a Democrat? How would you
answer that question since you're in a
similar position?
>> Uh, I think that um we
for first of all it's not it's not um
it's not a logistical
or a technocratic question running as a
Democrat or not. It is a political
question and given how rotten the
Democratic Party has exposed itself to
be. I mean, we're talking about a party
for whose candidate 19 million people
who had voted for Biden in 2020 refused
to vote at all in the election last year
because they were infuriated about the
genocide in Gaza and the cost of living
crisis. How does it it how does it do
any service to your credibility if
you're running to be a working-class
fighter to be part of the Democratic
party? So, I I completely disagree with
any candidates who say, you know,
perpetually are running for the working
class, but then say, oh, you know, like
just for logistical reasons, I want to
run as a Democrat. No, that doesn't work
because what message are you sending to
the D to the to the working class about
the you know the main message that you
have to send is you need a break from
you need to break from both the
Democratic and Republican parties.
They're both parties of billionaires and
we need an independent working-class
party of our own. And the starting point
of that it's not going to fall from the
sky. You know, this new party is not
going to fall from the sky. The way the
left parties were built in Europe, for
example, were through militant labor
movements and militant organizing by the
working class, especially with a
revolutionary character, you know, in in
the wake of the Russian revolution. And
so that is the kind of movement building
we need to do. And as part of that
movement building, we need to run
strong, really strong independent
working-class campaigns in election
years. And so, uh, running as a Democrat
sense goes in the exact opposite
direction. So, it is very much a
non-starter as far I'm as I'm concerned.
I mean, you have to run as an
independent. I run always run as an
independent. I'm running as an
independent now. The key is to build to
have really strong working-class demands
and to build a ground campaign that has
that that energizes thousands upon
thousands of people. That's how we have
won.
>> Okay. But I I agree with you [laughter]
obviously, but people are asking
logistically and let's let's say that
they're not asking because they don't
want people to run as independents, but
they want to fix the barriers that
independents face when they run outside
of the two-party system. So, can you
speak to what barriers, what limits,
what what obstacles you encounter not
running within the duopoly? Are you
going to be are there ballot access
issues? Are you going to be allowed to
participate in debates? Do you have to
um contend with being sort of
invisibleized by the media? You know,
those are the things that people want to
know as they're considering whether to
put time, energy, and effort into these
campaigns. You know, what is what is the
nature of the battle we're up against?
And what kind of commitment is it going
to take for me to make sure an
independent candidate actually has a
shot?
>> Yeah. I I mean obviously look we we have
to uh I I reject running as a Democrat
for any reason and especially you know
if you're saying oh well I don't believe
in the Democratic party but I'm just
doing it logistically. I think that is a
completely wrong starting point. But
that doesn't mean that we shouldn't be
strategic. We also we do have to be
strategic. If we want to win for the
working class then we have to be
strategic. And part of being strategic
means that you have to pick the right
kind of camp um races for yourself. you
know, you have you have to see which
race actually works. So, I'm not I'm not
my contention is not that, oh, there are
no barriers and you can run anywhere at
any time. That's not my contention. In
fact, my contention is, if anything, the
opposite in the sense that I don't think
it makes sense if we're actually trying
to build a powerful left, which I think
is absolutely urgently necessary, which
I'm sure you'll agree with me. Uh I
don't think the strategy is to run lots
and lots of candidates, independent or
otherwise. That is not the way it works.
I think what we need is a few very
strong candid candidates and very strong
campaigns and in strategic races where
we have a real uh ability to build
strong campaigns. I'm not saying that it
the necessary is to your
>> No, I understand. I I really this is a
good faith question. I just people want
to know. Let me just ask one question at
a time. Are you going to be on the
ballot? Is it is it going to be
difficult for someone like Andre Easton
to be on the ballot?
>> Uh I I don't I mean I I'll answer that
question, but as far as first your
question about me in Washington state,
it is what's called a jungle primary. So
I will be in the same primary as every
other candidate. The Republican
candidates will be in the same primary
>> and the top two whichever party
affiliation they have will move on to
the general election. I'm running as an
independent socialist and I believe on
the ballot it will show up as
independent. So uh yeah, I mean that's
what I mean by strategic, you know. So
I'm not claiming that every race is up
for grabs. In fact, it's the exact
opposite. It's very hard as far as
barriers are concerned. Trust me, the
barriers are extremely hard to overcome.
But the way you My point is not my
disagreement is not that the barriers
aren't hard. I I I'm compassionate to
the people who are saying that. My point
is that overcoming the barriers cannot
start with running as a Democrat. That's
what I'm saying. that yes, the barriers
are steep, but overcoming the Democrats,
first of all, you have to not run as a
Democrat and then
>> you have to build a working-class
campaign in order to get through. And
just one other thing I was going to say
about the New York I mean about the
Richie Torres race where it's not a
jungle primary and you you know that's
why people are making this conclusion
that they should run as uh run in the
Democratic primary. Well, but look uh
what is their what is their claim here?
I mean, are are you are they saying that
they are going to be able to defeat
Richie Torres uh in the Democratic
primary without an
>> absolutely I want to be let me clarify
even further. I'm asking you to dispel
people's skepticism that it is wrong to
run outside of the Democratic party. I
didn't ask the candidate this and maybe
it's not fair to ask you because you're
not as familiar with what's going on in
New York, but I'm asking this question
from the posture of reassure. I would
like you to reassure people by talking
about the value of or the the ability to
overcome certain obstacles despite
running as an independent. I'm not
asking this as a gotcha like as to why
you should run. Quite the opposite. I
know that people want to hear it's okay
and good that he's running as an
independent because X Y and Z and that
realistically speaking you have to get
let's say maybe an independent candidate
in New York has to get this number of
signatures or something something but it
that it can be done and that's that's
what I'm trying to to clarify that it
can be done without just erasing the
obstacles that are in front of us.
>> Yeah. Well, well, first of all, just if
you look at the um the mass
consciousness at this moment and
especially now, right now in in cities
like New York, I mean, people want
independent parties. I mean, I just saw
polling from North Carolina. I mean,
this is not the election results, but
other polls in North Carolina of all
places where it's they're saying that in
voter registrations, Republicans have
fallen flat. I mean, registering as
Republican party voters is fallen flat.
registering as Democratic party voters
is actually going down and what is going
up the only thing that's going up is
registering as an independent voter. So
for God's sake if at this moment we
don't recognize that running as an
independent is um feather in your cap
then I don't know when we will see that.
So first of all that is the starting
point. I mean, if you want reassurance
that you should run as an independent,
yes, please, at this moment, absolutely,
you need to. But in addition, it's not
enough just to run as an independent on
paper. You've got to build that campaign
that shows you as relentlessly
campaigning against whichever douchebag
Democrat you're running against. I mean,
in in Washington state in the ninth
congressional district, we are being
very clear. I mean, uh, am I trying to
make overtures to the Democratic party
and being only sort of u, you know,
marginally critical about my opponent,
Adam Smith? No, absolutely not. We are
making it crystal clear Adam Smith is a
genocidal billionaire backed Democrat
who actually should be on trial for war
crimes, but the very least the price he
needs to pay is to be thrown out of
office. This is how we are speaking. We
are campaigning openly for free
healthcare for all funded by taxing the
rich to end all US military aid to
Israel and you know to end the brutal
occupation. These so you bring up these
demands and people are like oh my god
this is the kind of campaign I want to
see. So I have I mean obviously the
rules in New York state elections are
different but the point is that the
political
uh sort of approach that we are putting
forward that is a universal thing. It's
not something specific to Washington
State.
>> Sha, as we wrap here, I was going to
maybe try to hang around for some kind
of Zuron speech, but I don't see
anything percolating. And y'all know
that I have to close my rings and I only
got another hour and a half before
midnight to do so. So, I want to close
by asking you this. if you were to be
giving advice to Zoron or were in
Zoron's position where he does have this
really loudable I do want to credit what
he's done to distinguish himself from
other progressives like the rest of the
squad AOC etc which is that he didn't
win just because it was a low and I
don't mean to diminish AOC either but
you know it wasn't just that it was a
low turnout election and where he caught
people off guard
um it was that he got in the in the
primary 50,000 in the balloon to you
said Shama 100,000 volunteers when I
visited New York in January and stayed
at Katy Hoverver's mom's place. I noted
that there were flyers in the door in
January. This is before he anyone knew
who he was. He was pulling in single
digits. You know, he was really doing
the work on the ground. He continued to
facilitate
and to and to grow and attend to those
volunteers and he really does have a
very galvanized army behind him. We'll
wait and see what he does with it. But
what would you say to him if you were in
this position where you had 100,000 New
Yorkers behind you? You're about to give
this speech tonight. You're going to be
the mayor sitting Gracie Mansion
shortly. What What do you want to see
from him or what would you do if you
were similarly situated?
>> I mean, it's very very straightforward
and simple. If he uh if he asked for my
advice, I would say use your army of the
working class in New York to fight for
the demands you have brought forward.
It's as simple as that. Use your army to
fight to win the demands you have
brought forward. Obviously underneath
that it lies that's where you know
that's where the rubber hits the road
because if you bu if you use that army
to actually fight fight to win those
demands then that is when the hard
questions start coming up because that
is when it pits you against the Kathy
Hokll and the Chuck Schumers and the
Hakee Jeff and the Tishes and all the
other billionaires and Wall Street
whichever you know centiers and
everything that that's when you come up
against all those forces. So uh uh you
know exactly what you know to do what
what we have done. I mean very first
question you know most immediate
question is can you turn your
inauguration into a mass rally and
announce the next steps for the fight
for whichever one of those demands you
know maybe start with free buses you
know whichever one you think is
strategically the best starting point.
announce the crucial next steps. You
know, rally people, tell people,
announce a date where people should come
in the tens of thousands to city hall
and rally for that particular demand.
Capture as much momentum as you can from
the election victory as you possibly can
and then turn it to the battle against
Wall Street.
Yeah. A a amen to that. I see people are
really enjoying your voice, Shamba. Uh
Stu says Shamasant was right. Um here we
have Stu again saying uh this I think as
in response to the clip we played of
Zoron talking about the police
commissioner uh earlier. 100% a dodge. I
hate it when we treat polit politicians
like they're naive. This man is not
naive. He's highly intelligent and a
very crafty politician. Just look at
what he's accomplished. Turnout.
Yeah. Um
yeah. Uh, Jean here says, "Love both
with Bri and Nathan. This is the highest
level of broadcast tonight. I prefer the
philosophical discussion to the others
and you guys are dressed just fine." Um,
I appreciate all of these uh comments.
Uh, but Shamba, I I I have to I have to
say that your voice is always in the
back of my mind
and I think it's because you have a kind
of moral clarity that I find to be
absent in most spaces. And I know that
Amanda
really I I appreciate her as well. Even
when we disagree on things from time to
time, I know that she's being guided by
a really um
well well tuned moral compass and she
can be persuaded on things but not about
whose lives matter [laughter]
and um what she's willing to compromise
on in terms of basic human rights and
dignity and is not drawn primarily I
think that there's a real I think
there's a real danger
and prioritizing winning above all else.
And there's a kind of meme that's going
around about the left that says like the
left doesn't care about winning. I think
Contra points famously tweeted this out
before she got blowback and left Twitter
that the left doesn't care about
winning. They just want to be right on
the internet. And I think that's wrong
and a very dangerous kind of centrist
response to saying that we shouldn't win
at any cost. And I really appreciate
Nathan also bringing up this in his
article against centism where he points
out that if you tried to poll test
equality, anti-slavery, the civil rights
movement, those would have also failed
in the polls. And at a certain point,
you have to learn to win without losing
all there is worth fighting for.
So I appreciate deeply your moral
clarity and your willingness to join us
here tonight. Before you go, do you want
to tell the audience where they can find
out more about you and your campaign?
Yes. Uh people can go to shama sawant my
first name last name no spaces.org to
find out about the campaign and if you
like what uh you heard then please join
worker strikeback also you can go to
workerstrikeback.org ORG that's our
national organization and if I might
just say Bri uh you know your question
about you know is it the left doesn't
know how to win obviously that's not
true the left has won many times that is
that is the only reason progress has
been made under capitalism and just to
reframe your question you know what's
what is important what is what we should
be prioritizing is winning at all costs
for the working class and for a better
society that should be done at all costs
meaning at all costs Should we avoid
selling out? It's very simple.
>> Thank you, Shamba. Thanks for everyone
for tuning in. I'm going to let you go,
Shama. I'm going to read the last of
these questions that I didn't get to and
then I'm going to let you guys all go
while I uh hop on the treadmill. So,
thank you again. Uh you have to come
back and talk to us again soon, but have
a great night.
>> You too. Bye. Bye.
>> Bye. Bye. Okay. And the last ones here
were just uh maybe just this one. Love
this. Bri, Nathan, and Amanda, my
favorite super group. Please do a live
Inerson podcast. I would love to do more
Inerson podcasts. I'm working on that uh
in the coming year. Uh I think I might
have read this one from Kimmy already.
Uh this one from Brandai, my brother. I
cannot forget. Thanks, Brandon. Um I
think that is everybody. So I'll leave
you with uh this. I did just recently do
um a interview with uh Mark Lamont Hill
over on his show on Al Jazer which I
strongly recommend you go and listen to.
It's only about 25 minutes long. I think
it really summarizes a lot of these
points. If you have people in your life
that you're trying to kind of get on
board with this left agenda and why the
Democratic party uh has limits, I would
encourage you to share that with them. I
also secretly would love a hosting gig
with AJ and I want the numbers in that
video to go up so they can tell how much
their audience really likes me. So, you
can help me out there. Don't forget to
like and subscribe to this um video and
subscribe to this channel. You know, the
algorithm is playing games with us. Hit
the bell if you haven't already done so.
Uh I was also interviewed for two Alzero
documentaries. One about Zoron is
already out and one is coming out
following election night. um they you
know had to see if he was going to win
or not before they let that one out. So
keep your eyes peeled for that. Uh on
Thursday I have an extended debate with
Osa Noevu of uh the New Republic. He's a
great writer. He's wrote a new book that
engages directly with the arguments in
the Ezra Klein article that we talked
about tonight about democracy and the
path forward for the left. But we have,
you know, obviously some difference of
opinion about the value of electoral
politics and how much confidence you
should have in someone within the
Democratic party and the Democratic
party itself to evolve in ways that
actually achieve progress. Um, he does a
really good job in the book walking
through the kind of democratic reforms
the Democrats could take on if they
cared really about democracy. And I make
the point that these were all at Biden's
disposal as he had a trifecta. He chose
not to deploy them. and what does that
mean about the existence of a legitimate
resistance party and should we continue
to feed into the idea that we have one?
So, I encourage you all to also
subscribe to the channel so you don't
miss that episode dropping. And as I
said before, I'm very proud of this
astrology episode. If you did not click
on it because you thought this was not
for you, I promise you that you will be
pleasantly surprised. As so many people
over on Patreon said, I don't care about
this stuff, yada yada, it's flaky d.
They were like, "This was one of the
best episodes of the year." They also
said that about my episode with Amanda
Seals. Uh, so you should go and listen
to that if you haven't done so already.
All right, that's my pitch. Thanks to
all of you who have been subscribing
over at Patreon. You know, if you enjoy
your free Thursday episodes, you can get
an extra episode over on Mondays at
patreon.com/badfaith
podcast. I will leave you with that.
Good night. Congratulations to Zaramani.
I hope that all the skepticism that has
been articulated over the last two and a
half episodes is ill-placed, that I'm
wrong about everything, and that you
live up to the fullest potential of what
you've worked so hard for and achieved
with an incredible amount of grace and
poise and raw political talent. I look
forward to seeing what you do next. Take
care, everybody, and as always, keep the
faith.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Heat. Heat.
Heat. Heat.